So I want to talk today about the memcache,
所以今天我想讨论一下 memcache ，
this is a paper from Facebook from 2013,
这是一篇来自 Facebook 的 2013 年的论文，
memcache are still widely used in many websites
memcache 在很多网站中使用，
or big Internet websites [] use
或者大型网站使用的，
have ideas or architecture is very similar to it.
与它的想法或架构很相似。
The paper is an experience paper,
这篇论文是一篇经验论文，
so the goal of the paper is not so much
所以，这篇论文的目的并不是
to introduce new ideas or new concepts or new innovative ways of building systems,
介绍构建系统的新思想，新概念或新的创新方式，
there's more to report on actual practical experience in trying to build systems,
这更多是构建系统的实践经验的总结，
that in this particular case,
在这种情况下，
can have support a billion requests per seconds or multiple billion requests per seconds.
可以支持每秒 10 亿个请求或每秒数十亿个请求。
And so there are three lessons,
这里有三个经验，
you know you can take away from this particular paper.
你可以从论文中学到的。
One is they got very impressive performance,
一是他们获得了令人印象深刻的性能，
out of building, out of building system with off the shelf component,
使用现成组件构建的系统，
so the system consist of standard open software packages,
系统由标准的开放软件组成，
like MySQL memcached,
比如 MySQL memcached ，
and they combine that together
他们把它们结合在一起，
to actually build a system
构建了一个系统，
or scale that out to a system,
或者向外扩展了一个系统，
that actually support a billion requests per seconds.
支持每秒 10 亿个请求。
As you can see, as we see in this lecture,
正如你所看到的，正如我们在这节课中所看到的，
there's sort of continuously in tension between performance and consistency,
在性能和一致性之间有一种持续的紧张关系，
and as you'll see in this paper,
正如你将在这篇论文中看到的，
the design is mostly driven by performance,
这个设计主要受性能驱动，
you know they want to find some degree of consistency,
他们想要找到某种程度的一致性，
is sort of added to,
某种程度上增加，
you know make the system at least be usable for the application that actually Facebook has,
使系统至少对 Facebook 使用的应用可用，
in fact, you know the consistency model
事实上，这里的一致性模型
is quite different from the consistency models that we've seen before,
与我们以前看到的一致性模型有很大不同，
most of the system we talked about so far
我们到目前为止讨论的大多数系统
actually provides either external consistency or linearizability,
要么提供外部一致性，要么提供线性一致性，
they're very strong for consistency,
它们在一致性方面非常强大，
and then in the case of Facebook,
在 Facebook 的案例中，
their applications don't really need linearizability,
它们的应用程序并不真正需要线性一致性，
if the user is reading news articles,
如果用户阅读新闻文章，
and the news feed is a couple of seconds behind,
而新闻消息落后了几秒钟，
it doesn't really matter,
这真的不重要，
and so they are, they have absolutely not the goal
所以，它们的目标不是
of providing sort of linearizability or strict consistency,
提供某种线性一致性或严格的一致性，
so that's an important thing to keep in mind.
所以，这是一件需要记住的重要事情。
Despite that they're not shooting for strong you know consistency,
尽管他们不是在追求强一致性，
there are some sort of cautionary tales in the paper,
在论文中仍然有一些警示故事，
that you know adding consistency measures is not easy,
添加一致性度量并不容易，
and you should not have, prepared for it to start,
你不需要，为它的开始做好准备，
but nevertheless, you know the you really can't argue with the success of the system,
但无论如何，你不能对这个系统的成功提出异议，
it really very successful,
它真的非常成功，
and allows Facebook websites you know follower,
允许 Facebook 网站的跟随者，
there is a couple the follow similar strategies
有很多使用相同策略，
to actually scaled a large large number of users.
能够扩大大量的用户。
So my plan for this lecture basically first to talk about performance,
所以我这次课程的计划是先谈谈性能，
because really the performance is the driving force behind this design,
因为性能才是这个设计背后的驱动力，
and then at the end you know talk more about consistency.
然后在最后更多地谈论一致性。
Before jumping into,
在开始之前，
let me know if there's any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Okay, so, let me start with a little bit of [] introduction to performance,
好的，让我从[]性能介绍开始，
and basically talk about website evolution.
谈谈网站的演变。
I'm sure many of you actually have built websites,
我相信你们中的许多人建立过网站，
and you know if you sort of start out,
如果你一开始，
and you don't have any users,
你没有任何用户，
you know that's pretty straightforward,
这很简单，
buy a machine or run a machine on Amazon or anywhere else,
在 Amazon 或其他任何地方购买或运行一台机器，
and you just basically need three components,
你基本上只需要三个组件，
you need web server, let's say Apache,
你需要网络服务器，比如 Apache ，
you need an application framework to build your website in,
你需要一个应用程序框架来构建你的网站，
maybe PHP, maybe Python,
可能是 PHP ，可能是 Python ，
you know in case of Facebook, I think they use PHP,
在 Facebook 的情况下，我想他们使用的是 PHP ，
and you need a database that actually stores the data of your website,
你需要一个数据库来存储你网站的数据，
you know for example use whatever MySQL,
比如使用 MySQL ，
that's you know Facebook is doing.
这是 FaceBook 所使用的。
And so you know clients you know connect to your website,
客户端连接到你的网站，
run you know the whatever application code
运行应用程序代码，
or whatever application service the website provides,
或者网站提供的任何应用程序服务，
and store and retrieve data using the database,
并使用数据库存储和查找数据，
the database provides transactions,
数据库提供事务，
it has SQL,
它有 SQL ，
so it's easy to query over the data in different ways,
所以，它可以很容易地以不同的方式查询数据，
and all the persistent state you know store in the database,
所有持久化状态都存储在数据库中，
so you know to backup the database,
为了备份数据库，
and you basically have a good sort of fault tolerance plan.
你会有一个很好的容错方案。
And that's sort of, and for any website,
这在某种程度上，对于任何网站来说，
that's small number of users is completely sufficient,
对于少量的用户是完全足够的，
and the way many websites are built,
许多网站的构建方式，
however you know when the, the number of users increases,
但是当用户数量增加的时候，
you probably need to go to a little bit more sophisticated design.
你可能需要进行更复杂的设计。
So this is sort of step one in the evolution.
所以这是演化的第一步。
In step two,
在第二步中，
sort of trying to address getting the first bottleneck that we're run into,
为了解决我们面临的第一个瓶颈问题，
when you have a larger number of users,
当你的用户数量较多时，
and typically the bottleneck you are run into
通常你遇到的瓶颈，
is basically the computation of cycles being used by the application,
是应用程序使用的计算周期，
so if you have thousands of users running at the website at the same time
如果你有数千名用户同时在网站上运行，
or 10,000 or whatever number of users it is,
或 10,000 或任何数量的用户，
and you know just running you know the application code
运行应用程序代码
on a single CPU or a single computer,
在单个 CPU 或单个计算机上，
gets to drive basically CPU you know load up 200%,
导致 CPU 负载到 200% ，
then you can't support more.
你就不能支持更多了。
And so, fortunately this is actually straightforwardly solved,
幸运的是，这很容易解决，
because the database actually has all the persistent state,
因为数据库具有所有持久状态，
so typically way you solve this is,
所以通常你解决这个问题的方法是，
you know you keep the one machine with the database run,
你保持一台机器运行数据库，
keep the machine on the database,
保持数据库机器，
and then just buy a bunch of different machines for the frontends,
然后为前端买一些机器，
I'm just going to talk about the frontend, that is one thing,
我说的到前端，是一种东西，
which is you know typically the website Apache plus you know some application code,
网站、 Apache 加上一些应用程序代码，
if you get more users, you'll buy more machines,
如果你有更多的用户，你买更多的机器，
you know they all connect to the database you know to get their data,
它们都连接到数据库来获取数据，
and and actually this design works out extremely well,
实际上，这个设计效果非常好，
because basically the frontends are stateless,
因为前端是无状态的，
you know all this data again is in the database,
所有这些数据都在数据库里，
and so adding a new server, it's pretty trivial,
添加一台新服务器是微不足道的，
all the frontends actually will see the latest writes,
所有前端都会看到最新的写入，
because all the data is actually stored in the database,
因为所有数据都存储在数据库中，
so there's no consistency issues,
所以不存在一致性问题，
in terms of fault tolerance is easy,
在容错方面很容易，
if one of these machines fails,
如果其中一台机器出现故障，
you know no problem at all,
完全没有问题，
and maybe the machines have to take over the load,
可能机器必须接管负载，
or you have to bring on a new machine of frontend,
或者你必须起一台机器给前端，
but you don't actually have to do anything
但是你不需要做任何事情，
in terms of complicated data restoration or restoration,
在复杂的数据恢复方面，
because all the data is actually in the database.
因为所有数据都在数据库中。
And so this is,
所以这是，
good, typically does the first thing that happens
好的，发生的第一件事，
and as a website you know scales.
随着网站规模发展。
Of course, as your website scales further,
当然，随着你的网站规模进一步扩大，
and you need to support more than say,
你需要支持超过，
you know for example a simple MySQL setup
比如，一个简单的 MySQL 设置
can probably support hundred thousand you know simple read transactions or simple read queries you know per second,
可能支持每秒十万的简单读事务或简单读查询，
probably you know thousands you know write transactions,
可能支持上千的写事务，
and so if the total number requests from your users actually goes over hundred thousand,
如果来自你的用户的请求总数超过十万，
then you need a different plan.
然后，你需要一个不同的方案。
And so, then the next plan is typically is sharding.
所以，下一个方案是分片。
And you know so far this is all pretty standard,
到目前为止，这一切都是相当标准的，
and so what you do is
所以你要做的是，
actually take the storage machine be split in multiple machines,
把存储机器分为多台机器，
the frontends basically stay the same,
前端保持不变，
we still have are many frontend machines,
我们仍然有很多前端机器，
and you know here we have are sharded database,
这里我们有分片数据库，
and basically you know some range of keys lives on,
一些键位于，
whatever maybe 1 to 40 live on you know shard 1,
可能 1 到 40 位于分片 1 ，
might from 40 to whatever 70 live on shard 2,
可能 40 到 70 位于分片 2 ，
and 70 to 100, you know just to make step up, live on shard 3,
进一步， 70 到 100 位于分片 3 ，
so basically you take the tables in the database or the rows in the database
你获取数据库中的表或数据库中的行，
and sharded by key.
并按键进行分片。
And so when the frontend needs to know,
所以，前端需要知道，
of course, which database there are
哪个数据库，
and you know that it needs to get you know key 32, you know it will go to shard 1,
它需要获取键 32 ，会去分片 1 ，
it needs to get you know to key 50, it will go to shard 2.
它需要获取键 50 ，会去分片 2 。
And so this gives us database parallelism,
所以，这为我们提供了数据库并行性，
so like every, in most request actually are on two different shards,
所以大多数请求都在两个不同分片上，
you know basically instead of actually limited by the one machine,
而不是被一台机器所限制，
we're actually getting the throughput
我们得到的吞吐量，
of one machine, say a hundred thousand
一台机器比如是十万，
times you know the number of machines that we have.
乘以我们有的机器数量。
And so that is typically the next step,
所以这是下一步，
and of course this actually has,
当然这是，
this step is a little bit more painful than the first step,
这一步比第一步更困难，
because now you might actually have cross-shard transactions,
因为现在你可能有跨分片事务，
if you need them,
如果你需要它们，
or if you want to avoid them,
或者如果你想避免它们，
you got group the keys you know that go go together on the same machine,
你可以对键分组放在同一台机器上，
otherwise, you know you need some two-phase commit protocol,
否则，你需要一些两阶段提交协议，
if you do transaction cross-shard,
如果使用事跨分片事务，
so, this, this step [] you know design two to design three,
所以，这一步从设计二到设计三，
is a significant, a significant step.
是非常重要的一步。
Now, if you grow further and further,
现在，如果你扩展更大，
you might say well,
你可能会说，
you know you could just shard the database further and further,
你可以把数据库分片更多，
sort of fewer key, keys per server,
每台服务器的键更少，
but that actually increases you know the risk,
但这增加了风险，
that you actually have to do cross-shard transactions.
你必须进行跨分片事务。
So there's another way of going,
还有一条路可以走，
which is observed like well,
观察到，比如，
maybe it's not really important,
也许这并不重要，
that the database actually supports the reads,
数据库支持读取，
you know we can offload the reads you know from the database,
我们可以从数据库中卸载读取，
and basically the database only does the writes,
数据库只进行写操作，
then maybe we can get a big performance gain.
那么也许我们可以获得很大的性能提升。
And so that's basically the next common step that the websites take,
所以，这是网站采取的下一个常见步骤，
if they scale up,
如果它们扩展，
is you know add cache,
添加缓存，
and you know it could be in the form of memcached or redis,
它可以是 memcached 或 redis 的形式，
you know sort of popular you know open-source packages for caching.
一种流行的用于缓存的开源软件。
And and then the basic plan is,
然后基本的计划是，
you know so is roughly as follows,
大致是这样的，
you have a lot of frontends as before,
跟前面一样，你有很多前端，
and we have a set of caches on the side,
我们在边上有一些缓存，
we'll talk a little bit about that in a second bit more,
稍后我们会更详细地讨论这一点，
in case case, we get here caches, cache layer,
在这种情况下，我们有缓存层，
cache 1, cache 2, cache 3,
缓存 1 ，缓存 2 ，缓存 3 ，
and in the case of Facebook, these are called,
在 Facebook 的案例中，这些被称为，
each individual server is called memcached daemon,
每个单独的服务器被称为 memcached 守护进程，
and the whole cluster or the collection of cache is called memcache.
整个缓存集群称为 memcache 。
And you know there's still our database
我们的数据库仍然存在，
you know sharded across maybe multiple machines,
分片在多台机器上，
there's sort of a storage layer.
这是一个存储层。
And so the idea is you know pretty straightforward,
所以想法很简单，
if you know frontend needs to, want to read a particular key,
如果前端需要读取特定的键，
you know first read to cache,
首先从缓存读取，
and hopefully you know will hit in the cache,
希望会命中缓存，
so basically get a quick response back you know from the cache,
从缓存中得到一个快速的回复，
if it's not in the cache,
如果它不在缓存中，
and it can retrieve it you know from the storage system,
它可以从存储系统中获取数据，
and then install you know the data in the cache,
然后把数据安装到缓存中，
writes you know basically go straight to the storage server.
写数据会直接发送到存储服务器。
And, this, you know this sort of kind of design,
这个设计，
we'll talk about it much more in the details in a second,
稍后我们将更详细地讨论它，
but this sort of design where you have a caching layer
但是这种带有缓存层的设计
works extremely well for read heavy workloads,
非常适合重读的工作负载，
and so if you think about Facebook,
如果你想一想 Facebook ，
it is going to be you know a whole lot of users,
将是很多用户，
and what they're doing is reading out of people's posts,
他们所做的就是阅读人们的帖子，
you know looking at the timelines,
查看时间线，
you know maybe watching looking at pictures,
也许查看照片，
reading the news, articles etc etc,
阅读新闻、文章等，
so it's very heavily oriented, workload oriented to read,
所以它是面向读取的繁重的工作负载，
and you know in this case,
在这种情况下，
you know the read to be almost served from these caches,
读取几乎都是来自缓存的，
and these caches can be like dirt simple.
这些缓存可能非常简单。
And think about like the caching,
想像一下缓存，
the key value server you built in lab 3,
你在实验 3 中构建的键值服务器，
you know the key value server itself is actually nothing more than a hash table,
键值服务器本身只是一个哈希表，
maybe you know you want to be a little bit smart about,
也许你想要聪明一点，
having locks for [],
对[]加上锁，
and so you have a bunch of concurrency within the cache server itself
所以，你在缓存服务器中有并发性，
or the key value server itself,
或者键值服务器，
but it is basically pretty straightforward.
但它是相当简单的。
There are two challenges that come along with this,
随之而来的是两个挑战，
where the main challenge basically is
其中的主要挑战是，
how to keep the database and the cache consistent.
如何保持数据库和缓存的一致性。
That's sort of challenge one,
这是第一个挑战，
you know a lot of the paper is devoted to talking about that.
很多论文都致力于谈论这一点。
And the second challenge,
第二个挑战，
which is also the main theme from the paper
也是这个论文的主题，
is how to make sure that the database doesn't get overloaded.
如何确保数据库不会超载。
And the the issue here is that,
这里的问题是，
once you know you scale up
一旦你扩展到，
say to a billion requests per second you know by using caches,,
通过使用缓存扩展到例如每秒 10 亿次，
if any of the caches fail,
如果任何缓存出现故障，
that load will shift you know from the frontend you know perhaps the database,
负载将从前台转移到数据库，
and of course you know the database is completely not designed
当然，数据库完全不是设计，
to support that kind of workload,
来支持这种工作负载，
basically will fall over.
基本上会倒下。
And so a key challenge in the whole set of lessons,
所以整个课程中的一个关键挑战，
that you learn from this particular paper
你从这篇论文中学到的，
is that techniques to basically avoid going to the database,
是避免访问数据库的技术，
so there's no risk that actually you overload the database.
所以，没有使数据库过载的风险。
Okay, any other questions so far?
好的，到目前为止，还有其他问题吗？
Let me say a little bit about consistency,
让我简单地说一下一致性，
because that will be,
因为那会是，
although I'm going to talk mostly about performance,
虽然我将主要讨论性能，
you know it's gonna be important to keep in mind,
记住这一点很重要，
even in the sort of section about consistency, about performance.
甚至在关于性能的部分。
Oh, I have a quick question, sorry,
哦，我有个小问题，抱歉，
goes back to, like having this state, like the clients be stateless,
回到比如客户端是无状态的，
so what,
那么,
yeah, there we go, on the second part of website solution,
是的，在网站解决方案的第二部分，
why is it important for the clients to be stateless?
为什么客户端必须是无状态的？
That makes the replication easy, right,
这使得复制变得很容易，
the clients don't actually, you don't replicate the data,
客户端不用，你不用复制数据，
so you don't have to keep the data consistent,
所以，你不必保持数据的一致性，
you know all data lives in one place,
所有的数据都在一个地方，
maybe there is a database server.
也许这里有一个数据库服务器。
Okay, yeah, so the idea is,
好的，所以这个想法是，
like any any client can fail and it doesn't matter.
任何客户都可以失败，这并不重要。
Yeah, it doesn't matter,
是的，这不重要，
you know keep going computing,
继续进行计算，
and you don't have to worry about actually keeping data consistent,
你不必担心保持数据的一致性，
because data is only in one place,
因为数据只在一个地方，
like a lot of the things we've been talking about this semester,
我们这学期谈到的很多事情，
doesn't show up in this particular design.
在这个设计中没有体现出来。
Okay?
好的?
Okay, so getting back to sort of,
好了，让我们回到，
once you do actually cache data,
一旦你缓存了数据，
you do have this consistency issue, right,
你就有了一致性问题，
and and so you know the instant question is,
所以当前的问题是，
like what database, what is Facebook shooting for.
Facebook 的目标是什么。
And something is typically called almost,
一些东西被称为，
like it's called eventual consistency,
它被称为最终一致性，
which a pretty vague term,
这是一个相当模糊的术语，
but basically you know maybe to contrast it is,
但是也许是为了对比一下，
to say it actually does not shoot for linearizability,
可以说，它并不追求线性一致性，
and in fact what they sort of shooting for is,
事实上，他们所追求的是，
you know they do want write ordering,
他们想要按顺序写入，
writes are all applies in some consistent you know total order,
写入是以某种一致的整体顺序来应用的，
so that you don't get weird going back in time problems,
你不会在时间问题上感到奇怪，
and that is all done basically by the database,
这些都是由数据库完成的，
so not really a big concern you know for the memcache layer itself.
对于 memcache 层来说，这并不是一个大问题。
In terms of reads, it's okay, if reads are behind,
在读取方面，如果读取落后也没关系，
and that is really the property of the applications,
这就是应用程序的属性，
that you know Facebook wants to support,
Facebook 想要支持的应用程序，
again you know the data that's in these caches,
再次，这些缓存中的数据，
the data that the user actually consume,
用户使用的数据，
web pages, post timelines, friend lists and all that kind of stuff, and or status,
网页、帖子时间表、朋友列表和所有类似的东西，或状态，
and none of that actually is really that important for users to see,
对于用户来说，这些都不是那么重要，
very, you know update your picture,
更新你的照片，
you know it is behind a little bit one or two seconds,
它稍微晚了一两秒，
no problem at all,
一点问题都没有,
certainly left behind for hundreds of milliseconds,
当然会落后几百毫秒的时间，
you know user won't even notice,
用户甚至不会注意到，
you know there's not perceptible,
不会察觉到，
and so it's okay to behind,
所以落后也没关系，
you know of course you don't want to be behind for hours,
当然你不想落后几个小时，
you know user might actually notice,
用户可能会注意到，
but you know for a little while behind,
但在一小段时间内落后，
this actually are not a particular big deal.
这并不是什么特别大的事情。
So they're not really shoot you know for serializability linearizability,
所以他们的不是为了线性一致性，
where read observe the last write,
读取观察到最新的写入，
you know [] some [] write, you know that's fine.
如果[]写入，这是可以的。
There's one exception to that,
但有一个例外，
which is that they do want to arrange that,
那就是他们想要安排，
you know sort of clients read their own writes,
客户端读取自己的写入，
and and meaning that you know if one client updates key k
这意味着如果一个客户端更新键 k
and then immediately read that at key k,
然后立即读取键 k ，
it's very desirable that client actually does observe its own write,
非常希望客户端观察自身的写入，
because actually makes it more complicated to,
因为这让事情变得更加复杂，
otherwise maybe [] would be even more complicated.
否则，[]可能会更加复杂。
So this is roughly what they're shooting for,
所以，这就是他们要争取的目标，
and you know just quite a bit weaker
只是稍微弱了一点，
than some of the models that we've seen before,
比我们以前见过的一些模型，
and remind me a little bit from the Zookeeper
让我想起 Zookeeper ，
sort of style of contract you know it can provide.
可以提供的合约风格。
Okay, so one other thing that I want to say,
好的，还有一件事我想说，
go back a little bit,
往回一点，
so we need to keep the databases in caches
我们需要将数据库保存在缓存中，
and cache consistency in some manner.
以某种方式保持缓存一致性。
Okay, so the basic plan that Facebook follows,
好的， Facebook 的基本方案是，
is an invalidation plan or cache invalidation plan.
是缓存失效方案。
And we'll see later in the lecture why that's the case,
我们会在后面的课程中看到，为什么是这样，
basically what happens, if the frontend does write,
发生的是，如果前端执行写入，
you know it goes actually to the database,
它进入数据库，
here's MySQL,
这是 MySQL ，
but they run on next to the database you know another program,
但他们在数据库旁边运行另一个程序，
whatever called squeal,
称为 squeal ，
and basically it looks at the transaction log,
它会查看事务日志，
so MySQL maintains transaction log you know to implement transactions,
MySQL 维护事务日志以实现事务，
and you know squeal looks like this transaction log, sees what things get modified,
squeal 查看这个事务日志，看看什么东西被修改了，
and basically if there's a key gets modified,
如果有一个键被修改，
so it seems like key k gets modified,
它看到键 k 被修改了，
it will send an invalidation message to the cache,
它向缓存发送失效消息，
basically deleting, actually it just issues a delete of that key k,
删除，它只是发送一个删除键 k ，
you know to the appropriate cache,
到合适的缓存，
and that way you know the data will be removed,
这样数据将被删除，
and then at some point later,
然后在之后的某个时候，
when a client comes along, does a read,
当客户端出现，执行读取，
it will get a miss in the cache,
它不会在缓存命中，
read retrieves the data from and read from there,
读取从这里查找数据，
so here it does get,
所以这里是 get ，
let me call this a get,
让我把这称为 get ，
there's a reed, gets the data from the read,
这里有一个 read ，从 read 获取数据，
and then actually installs it in the cache.
然后安装到缓存中。
And so one thing you might wonder,
所以，你可能会想，
like why actually does the application itself installed the data into the cache,
为什么应用程序自己将数据安装到缓存中，
so it does put,
所以它执行 put ，
and this has to do with actually these caches,
这与这些缓存有关，
you know what they call are look-aside caches,
他们所说的旁路缓存，
and the reason they're sort of look-aside is that,
它们是旁路的原因是，
because typically what the application will do
因为通常应用程序所做的，
with the data that actually read from the database,
数据从数据库中读取，实际从数据库中读取的数据，
it's maybe [] a little bit,
这有一点[]，
there's some computation on it,
它上面有一些计算，
and it'll take the text of the page,
它将获取页面的文本，
and actually turn it into an HTML page or HTML5,
将其转换为 HTML 页面或 HTML5 ，
and then store the result of that HTML version of the page actually into the cache,
然后将页面的 HTML 版本的结果存储到缓存中，
or maybe you know reads a bunch of different records
或者可能读取很多记录，
aggregates you know some data
聚合一些数据，
and you know puts the aggregated result into cache.
并将聚合结果放入缓存中。
So the application is sort of in control,
所以，应用程序控制，
in this design,
在这个设计中，
what to put in the cache,
将什么放入缓存中，
and it puts a little bit more burden on the frontend or in the application
这给前端或应用程序增加了负担，
or the client, in this case,
或者在这种情况下，在客户端中，
but it has the advantage,
但它有一个优势，
you know that you can sort of do some pre processing,
你可以做一些预处理，
before actually sticking something in the cache.
在把东西放入缓存之前。
And this sort of contrast, where the cache would be transparent,
在这个对比中，缓存是透明的，
where the cache would be sitting between the frontend and the storage server,
缓存位于前端和存储服务器之间，
and if you're missing the cache,
如果你错过了缓存，
then the cache will choose the data,
然后缓存将选择数据，
but of course the cache in the database
当然，数据库中的缓存
don't really know what the application exactly what's stored in the cache,
不知道应用程序到底在缓存中存储什么，
and so in the look-aside design,
所以，在旁路设计中，
this is the application is sort of control the cache.
是应用程序在控制缓存。
So a little bit more detail,
所以更详细一点，
we can look at this picture,
我们可以看看这个图片，
that looks like how actually read or write implemented.
看看读或写是如何实现的。
So here's read,
所以这是读取，
oops, sorry,
糟糕，抱歉，
so this is a figure 2 from the paper,
这是论文中的图 2 ，
and so here's our web servers or clients,
这是我们的网络服务器或客户端，
you know the clients to retrieve k for memcache,
客户端从 memcache 获取 k ，
as we'll see in a second,
我们稍后会看到，
they are typically actually will ask for a whole bunch of keys,
它们通常会请求很多键，
there's not uncommon,
这并不少见，
that you know the web server will ask for 20 to 100 of keys,
网络服务器要求 20 到 100 个键，
you know presumably and starting to compute some web page,
开始计算一些网页，
the web page contains aggregates data from lots of different places,
网页包含来自许多不同地方的聚合数据，
and for every piece of data,
对于每一条数据，
that needs to be put into that web page,
需要放到那个网页上，
the client issues,
客户发出，
the get request we've made perhaps with many many, many keys,
我们发出的 get 请求可能有很多很多键，
that goes to memcache,
它们会到 memcache ，
it gets results back,
它获取结果，
and when sending that get to memcache,
当发送那个 get 到 memcache ，
you know might contact many memcached servers,
可能会联系许多 memcached 服务器，
the results come back to the web server,
结果返回到网络服务器，
if if anything's missing,
如果有什么东西没有命中，
you know can process the ones,
可以处理那些，
that actually returns a [] result,
返回[]结果，
you know we can get nil back,
我们会得到 nil ，
then the client you know goes does select the database,
然后客户端向数据库 SELECT ，
runs a SQL query,
运行 SQL 查询，
that returns some data and the results,
它返回一些数据和结果，
you know that clients might do some computation,
客户端可能会进行一些计算，
and then actually install you know the process
然后安装进程，
and values that came back from the SELECT into memcache,
从 SELECT 获得的值到 memcache ，
that's sort of the read side.
这就是读取的方面。
Again and again here you can see the,
再一次，你可以在这里看到，
look look-aside property or aspect of this design,
这个设计的旁路属性或方面，
where memcache is not really sitting straight between the web server and database,
memcache 并不是直接位于网络服务器和数据库之间，
but sits on this side,
而是在旁边，
is managed by the client.
由客户端管理。
So here's the write side,
所以这是写入端，
so, for example, if the web server or the application needs to whatever add a post,
例如，如果网络服务器或应用程序需要添加帖子，
or you know put a picture in the post or whatever,
或者在帖子中放一张图片，
the server does updates,
服务器进行更新，
you know sends basically the update to the database,
将更新发送到数据库，
this is just performed like a normal transaction,
就像正常的事务一样执行，
and then of course the database on the side,
当然，在数据库旁边，
you know as we saw before,
像我们之前看到的，
will do invalidation,
将会导致失效，
using you know the squeal demon,
使用 squeal 守护程序，
and with that squeal daemon, you know operate asynchronously,
有了那个 squeal 守护程序，你可以异步操作，
oops, sorry,
糟糕，抱歉，
and so the client, the writers really wait until that invalidation is happen,
客户端，写入者等待失效发生，
once the update in the transaction,
一旦事务中的更新，
once the update is done in the database,
一旦数据库中的更新完成，
transaction is completely completed and returned to the client,
事务完成，并返回给客户端，
and then in parallel, the squeal actually, squeal will see the invalidation,
然后同时 squeal 会看到失效，
and and because you know the squeal does the invalidation asynchronously,
因为 squeal 以异步方式执行无效操作，
the web server just do [],
网络服务器执行[]，
does delete of the key in the cache immediately,
立即删除缓存中的键，
and so when the reason for that delete is
这个删除的原因是，
only because we want to read our own writes.
因为我们想要读取自己的写入。
So when the web server for example look for that key k,
所以，当网络服务器查找键 k 时，
right after it did the update,
就在它更新之后，
then it will miss in memcached
然后它将在 memcached 中丢失，
and it will go and actually retrieve new value and then install it,
它将获取新的值，然后安装它，
and but just a case,
但是只是这种情况，
where web server immediately reads its own, reads,
网络服务器立即读取它自己的，
that reads the key k that just actually updated a little while ago.
读取刚刚更新的 key k 。
Okay?
好的?
Where in principal is not necessary to do this delete,
原则上不需要执行这个删除，
the invalidation at some point will happen,
失效在某个时刻会发生，
and will kick out you know that key k out of cache,
将 key k 从缓存中删除，
and that's fine for basically other clients,
对于其他客户端来说，这是可以的，
but just with this client,
但是对于这个客户端，
we want to make sure that actually reads its own its own writes.
我们希望确保它能读取自己的写入。
I have a question,
我有个问题，
so why doesn't it set after the delete?
为什么不在删除后进行设置呢？
Yeah, that's a very good question,
是的，这是个好问题，
like why doesn't do update immediately, right,
为什么不立即更新，
and I think that so that's called update scheme,
我认为这就是所谓的更新方案，
and that's in principle possible here too,
原则上这在这里也是可能的，
but I think it's a little bit tricky for them to make work,
但我认为这对他们来说有点困难，
because I think it was going to require some cooperation
因为我认为这需要一些合作，
between the database, the cache and the client.
在数据库、缓存和客户端之间。
And I think the issue is follows,
我认为问题是这样的，
let's say we have a client C1,
假设我们有一个客户端 C1 ，
we have a client C2,
我们有一个客户端 C2 ，
and we'll see similar type [] showing up,
我们会看到类似的类型出现，
let's say client x 1,
假设客户端 x 1 ，
sets x to 1 and sends that to the database,
将 x 设置为 1 并将其发送到数据库，
and then, so like you know,
然后，比如，
like so this is a hypothetical update scheme,
这是一个假设的更新方案，
it's, the main point of this slide will be,
这张幻灯片的重点是，
or this board will be sort of talk about
或者这个白板讨论，
like doing actually update is not completely trivial,
执行更新不是无关紧要的，
let's say client 2 at the same time,
假设同时客户端 2 ，
we're running after it,
我们运行它，
says x to 2, sends that to the database,
将 x 设为 2 ，将其发送到数据库，
and let's say the client 1 has got a little bit delayed,
假设客户端 1 有一点延迟，
and so we're implement your scheme, correct,
所以我们实施你的方案，
then we immediately do set of k to 2,
然后我们立即执行设置 k 为 2 ，
and let me say k with 0 at the end in the beginning,
假设 k 在开始时是 0 ，
so this will update memcached, correct,
所以，这将更新 memcached ，
cache is now going to have a value of you know whatever k to 2,
缓存现在将有一个值 k 为 2 ，
then you know client 1 actually you know comes around to do actually it's set,
然后客户端 1 执行它的设置，
so it will do set here or put,
所以，它会放在这里 set 或 put ，
set, put, oops set k to 1,
set put ，糟糕，设置 k 为 1 ，
and so this will overwrite the 2,
这将覆盖 2 ，
and now we have a stale value in the cache,
现在我们在缓存中有一个旧的值，
and worse you know this value is there sort of persistently stale,
更糟糕的是，这个值是一直过时的，
you know any you know get later on will see actually the stale value.
任何之后的 get 将看到旧的值。
And so this is not so desirable,
所以，这不是所希望的，
and so you want to avoid that,
所以你想避免这种情况
and then of course you can make maybe update scheme work,
当然，你可以让更新方案起作用，
by for example you know ordering time stamping
比如，对时间戳排序，
or assigning a sequence number to the updates,
或者为更新分配序列号，
and then by the database,
然后通过数据库，
and then the key value server or memcached
然后键值服务器或 memcached
could basically not perform updates that are out of order,
可以不执行顺序之外的更新，
but a scheme like that was going to require some participation of the database,
但这样的方案需要数据库的一些参与，
I mean required modifications to MySQL,
我的意思是对 MySQL 进行必要的修改，
and one of their goals was to actually build everything from off the shelf components,
他们的目标之一是从现成的组件构建所有东西，
and so you know they prefer to go this invalidation scheme,
所以他们更喜欢这个失效方案，
which I think is just simpler to implement,
我认为这实施起来更简单，
because basically you know your database, the only thing it has to do
因为你的数据库唯一要做的，
is this additional process that sits on the side,
是这个额外的进程在旁边，
and uses the standard you know delete the operation,
并使用标准的删除操作，
that memcached already supports.
memcached 已经支持的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
And we'll see similar issue like this one show up later again, correct,
我们稍后会看到类似的问题再次出现，
because there's, you remember from the paper,
因为，你还记得从论文上看到，
there's some discussion about these tokens or leases,
有一些关于 token 或租约的讨论，
to deal with stale values,
为了处理陈旧的值，
but that's going to be,
但这将是，
as we'll see stale values on the read side,
我们将看到，旧值在读方面，
or stale values that sort of have interaction between readers or writers,
或者读取者和写入者之间交互的旧值，
but can be solved totally in the context of memcached
但是完全可以在 memcached 的上下文中解决，
without actually making any database modifications.
无需对数据库做任何修改。
So why do we have a separate process to basically issue the invalidation,
为什么我们要有一个单独的程序来发布失效，
so this squeal, I think it was called,
我想它被称为 squeal ，
so why so why do we have this process,
所以为什么我们有这个程序，
if the frontend itself will issue a delete k anyway?
如果前端本身发出删除 k ？
We'll see you later on,
我们稍后会看到，
why this is going to be very useful,
为什么这是非常有用的，
particularly what we're gonna do is,
尤其是我们要做的是，
we'll see is that the cache is going to be replicated,
我们将看到，缓存被复制，
and we need to set invalidation to every replica.
我们需要发送失效给每个复制。
Okay, I see, thank you.
好的，我明白了，谢谢。
Okay, squeal it's not gonna send a delete to every memcache replica?
好的， squeal 不会发送删除到每个复制吧？
The squeal, yeah,
squeal ，是的，
we'll see in a second,
我们一会儿会看到，
hold on and we'll see that in a second.
稍等，我们马上就会看到。
In fact, I'm gonna go talk about it right now.
事实上，我现在就要谈谈这件事。
So so so far actually most of the story is pretty standard,
到目前为止，大部分故事都是相当标准的，
you know small changes here,
这里的变化很小，
and what you know we've talked about so far,
我们到目前为止谈过的，
nothing really too exceptional,
没有什么特别的，
things get more interesting right after this,
在这之后事情就变得更有趣了，
and and so we get more into
所以，我们更深入地了解
sort of Facebook specific optimization or performance tricks.
Facebook 特定的优化或性能技巧。
And, one first thing that we're going to see,
我们要看到的第一件事是，
let me get this in order, [] to go back,
让我把这个整理好，[]放回去，
the first thing is actually sort of,
第一件事是，
becomes usual is that,
通常情况下，
actually Facebook basically replicates a complete data center,
Facebook 复制一个完整的数据中心，
at the time of the writing of this paper,
在编写这个论文的时候，
there were basically two data centers,
有两个数据中心，
one on the west coast,
一个在西海岸，
we switch back to blue,
我们换回蓝色，
so data center 1,
数据中心 1 ，
they called regions,
他们称为区域，
here's data center 2,
这是数据中心 2 ，
and they basically have you know, they're all have a client layer,
它们都有都有客户端层，
so a lot of frontends,
所以有很多前端，
and maybe this is the one on the west coast,
也许这是西海岸的那个，
and then you know this is the memcached or a memcache layer,
然后这是 memcached 或 memcache 层，
they both have their own memcache layer,
它们都有自己的 memcache 层，
so here there are frontends again, a lot of frontends,
所以这里也是前端，很多前端，
so here are a lot of memcacheds,
这里是很多 memcached ，
a lot of memcacheds,
很多 memcached ，
a lot of memcached here,
这里有很多 memcached ，
and then you know there's the storage layer,
然后这是存储层，
which are sort of sharded databases,
它是一种分片的数据库，
so a lot of machines here too,
这里也有很多机器，
and basically the data center 2, the one on the east coast,
数据中心 2 在东海岸，
is a direct replica of the one on the west coast,
是西海岸那个的直接复制品，
and, and the scheme that they use for write,
它们用来写入的方案，
because now we have two replica of the data, correct,
因为现在我们有两个数据副本，
data of the database stored in two places,
数据库的数据存储在两个地方，
so we need to keep in some way you know these two copies up to date,
所以我们需要以某种方式保持这两个副本同步，
and the basic plan at least on the right side is to
基本的方案至少在右边是，
all the writes are going through the primary,
所有写入都通过 primary ，
and one of the regions is primary, the other is a backup region,
其中一个区域是 primary ，另一个是 backup 区域，
so this is region 2,
这是区域 2 ，
the fact, I think the paper says the west coast is the primary,
事实上，我想论文说西海岸是 primary ，
and the east coast is the backup,
东海岸是 backup ，
and so all write actually go you know through the storage layer on the primary,
所以，所有写入都要通过 primary 的存储层，
so even writes you know issued by the frontends on the east coast,
所以即使是东海岸的前端发布的写入，
you know go to the database here,
会去这里的数据库，
so the database there on the primary just runs the transaction,
primary 上的数据库运行事务，
and you know and basically propagates you know these invalidation message,
传播这些失效消息，
well, first of all, takes the log that actually sits at this side
首先，在这边获取日志，
and basically copies or transmitted over to the other side,
然后复制或传输到另一边，
and so this is the squeal process,
这就是 squeal 进程，
that basically does that in,
它执行，
you know that process basically applies the log
这个进程将日志应用于
to storage in the database on the other side,
另一边数据库中的存储，
so keeping the two databases in sync,
使两个数据库保持同步，
and as a side effect,
并且作为连带作用，
it might actually send invalidation messages or delete messages to like k,
它可能发送失效消息或删除消息给 k ，
and so you might wonder like,
所以你可能会想，
why do it this way,
为什么要这样做，
you know why not keep for example everything on the west coast,
为什么不把所有东西放在西海岸，
and basically double the number of you know memcaches and all that kind of stuff.
而是两倍的 memcache 和所有东西。
You know the one primary reason to do this is,
这样做的一个主要原因是，
this good read performance for users,
对于用户来说，这种良好的读取性能，
good read performance for users actually sitting on east coast,
对于在东海岸的用户来说，读取性能很好，
you know the, they they will connect you know to one of these guys,
他们会连接这些中的一个，
they will look up the data in the cache,
他们在缓存中查找数据，
their memcache on the east coast,
他们的 memcache 在东海岸，
and basically return the data straight out of the memcache,
直接从 memcache 中返回数据，
so we're basically going to get really good,
所以我们会得到好的，
you know one we still get a good read performance,
一个是，我们得到好的读取性能，
in fact, we can also get low latency,
我们还可以获得低延迟，
because we're basically reading from a replica that's close by,
因为我们从附近的一个复制中读取数据，
of course, you know the these caches you might get a little bit more out of sync,
当然，这些缓存可能会有一点不同步，
than for example that in the same data center,
比起在一个数据中心，
because like this whole updates and invalidation,
因为像整个更新和失效，
you know all happens asynchronously,
都是异步发生的，
but, that's more or less a little bit okay, correct,
但是，这是可以的，
because we already said,
因为我们已经说过，
that we're actually not looking for you know strict consistency or or serializability.
我们不是在寻找严格的一致性或串行化。
I have a question,
我有个问题，
so, if, so, if someone in the east coast,
如果某人在东海岸，
or client in the east coast write,
东海岸的客户端写入，
it writes directly to to storage on west, right?
它会直接写到西海岸的存储，对吗？
Yeah.
是的。
Which, it doesn't invalidate.
但这并不会失效。
Okay, this guy also goes invalidate to each cache.
好的，这个会对每个缓存执行失效操作。
Oh, but we said, right,
哦，但我们说过，
but we said,
但我们说过，
like the client itself to read its own write, its own write.
客户端读取自己的写入。
Yeah, so where does that where does this go that,
是的，那么这个会去哪里，
of course goes to here, right.
当然会去这里。
Yeah, yeah, that makes sense, okay.
是的，理解了，好的。
Okay.
好的。
Okay?
好的?
I got a question too,
我也有个问题，
do clients always talk,
客户端是不是总是访问，
said, will given client always talk to the same memcache server?
比如，给定的客户端是否总是访问相同的 memcache 服务器？
No, because I'll go back a little bit earlier,
不，我往回一点，
and we'll talk about this in a second,
我们稍后会讨论这个问题，
because actually is a a problem as we'll see,
因为正如我们将看到的，这是一个问题，
so if a frontend basically talks,
所以，前端访问，
the the keys are sharded across the memcache servers, right,
键分片在 memcache 服务器上，
and so like whatever key k1,
比如键 k1 ，
k1 lives in C1,
k1 在 C1 上，
k2 lives in C2, etc etc,
k2 在 C2 上，等等，
and typically from then, when it needs to construct a web page,
当它需要组成一个网页时，
it needs to get a whole bunch of keys,
它需要很多键，
and so sends actually these requests basically parallel to the different memcacheds,
同时发送这些请求到不同的 memcached ，
and gets all the responses back,
然后获得所有的回复，
and the, and so in fact,
所以事实上，
you know the frontends are very likely to talk to every memcached in the system.
前端很可能会访问系统中每个 memcached 。
I see, but for, but for a given key,
我明白了，如果对于一个给定的键，
would always talk to the same server.
是否总是访问相同的服务器。
Yes, yeah, they they actually happened to use consistent hashing,
是的，他们使用了一致性哈希，
so if we'll talk a little bit about second a little bit more,
我们稍后会多谈一点，
like one of the one memcached server goes down, correct,
如果一个 memcached 服务器出现故障，
it can't talk to that one anymore,
它就不能访问那个了，
and so it might be over time,
所以，随着时间的推移，
that the assignment from shards to servers will change a little bit.
从分片到服务器的分配可能会发生一些变化。
Sorry, actually just to follow up on that,
抱歉，我想跟进一下，
so the requirement for clients to read their own writes,
所以客户端需要读取自己的写入内容，
is is kind of like a weak guarantee, right,
像是一种弱的保证，
because if the server that it deletes from goes down,
因为如果它从中删除的服务器停机，
and then it has to read from a different replica,
然后它必须从不同的复制中读取，
it might end up not reading its write,
它可能最终不能读取自己的写入内容，
if in the presence of a failure.
如果在出现故障时。
Hold on, hold on, hold that for a little while, okay,
稍等一下，好吗，
you know we'll see there's a number of [] or races,
我们会看到有一些[]或竞争，
if you will and they have different techniques for solving those races.
他们有不同的技术来解决这些竞争问题。
Oh, sorry, final question.
哦，抱歉，最后一个问题。
Yeah, final, go ahead.
是的，最后一个，继续。
Oh, so we're doing,
哦，所以我们在做，
we like for read for read our own writes,
我们为了读取自己的写入，
we make sure that we go directly to the storage servers,
我们确保直接访问存储服务器，
right after, right, correct?
正好在后面，对吗？
Yes.
是的。
Not in the cache,
不在缓存中，
but you also said the.
但你也说过。
No, hold on hold on,
不，稍等，
when you do write,
当你执行写入时，
you do the update in the database.
你在数据库中进行更新。
Right.
是的。
Then you delete the key from your system,
然后你从你的系统中删除键，
so for example in this particular case,
例如，在这个案例中，
you know you would you do a write you know to the primary,
你会写入到 primary ，
delete the key k from your local cache,
从你的本地缓存中删除键 k ，
so when the next time you do get,
所以当你下一次执行 get 时，
you're gonna read from the storage server again.
你将再次从存储服务器读取。
Right, exactly, yeah, but I was curious,
是的，没错，但我很好奇，
so that you also said,
所以你也说过，
the write to storage happen asynchronously, right?
对存储的写入是异步进行的，对吗？
The the, this this replication happens asynchronously
这个复制是异步进行的，
and the invalidation happens asynchronously,
失效是异步进行的，
not the write.
而不是写入。
Okay, the writes are synchronous.
好的，写入是同步的。
So, you do the delete after you finish the write.
所以，你在完成写入后执行删除。
Okay, great, thanks.
好的，很好，谢谢。
A question here,
有一个问题，
so if you do a write,
所以如果你执行写入，
and you're from the,
而你来自，
so you're not, you're not from the primary region,
你不是来自 primary 区域，
you do a write to the primary storage,
你向主存储执行写入操作，
and then you invalidate your memcache,
然后你失效你的 memcache ，
and then do a read,
然后进行读取，
but read from your storage,
但是从你的存储中读取，
and maybe your storage isn't up to date yet.
也许你的存储还不是最新的。
Yeah, so you gotta risk,
是的，所以有风险，
so we'll see how they solve that.
所以，我们将看他们如何解决这个问题的。
Okay.
好的。
That's correct,
没错，
but first let's talk more about performance,
但首先让我们更多地谈谈性能，
because it's not good enough for them yet,
因为这对他们来说还不够好，
they want more performance.
他们想要更高的性能。
And so you know if you sort of broadly speaking,
所以如果从广义上说，
there are two strategies to getting performance.
有两种策略可以获得性能。
I'm just stepping back a little bit,
我往后退一点，
we already seen them a little bit, in a very high level.
我们已经在高级别上看到了它们。
So there are two basically plan,
所以有两个方案，
one is to partition or shard,
一个是分区或分片，
and that's very cool,
这很酷，
because in fact we see this being use basically
因为我们看到这使用在
both on the storage layer and the memcache layer,
存储层和 memcache 层上，
and so if you you need more capacity,
如果你需要更多容量，
you should buy another server,
你应该再买一台服务器，
change the hashing function,
修改散列函数，
and so you've got more capacity in your memcached,
这样你的 memcached 中有了更多的容量，
and you can hold more data, right,
你可以保存更多的数据，
and that data can be accessed in parallel,
并且数据可以被并行访问，
so you know we've got a lot of capacity,
所以我们得到很大的容量，
lots of capacity, lots of parallelism side,
很大的容量，很大的并行性，
but you know if you have particular key that's extremely hot,
但是，如果你有非常热的键，
a lot of clients actually need to get that key,
很多客户端都需要获取那个键，
you know whatever a particular person on Facebook
无论是 Facebook 的特殊的人，
who has a timeline that everybody is you know following,
有一个每个人都关注的时间线，
then you know that that key is going to hit a lot,
然后那个键会命中很多次，
and it is being served,
它被提供服务，
[] in this case, being served maybe by two different servers,
在这种情况下，可能由两个不同的服务器提供服务，
one in the west coast, one on the east coast,
一个在西海岸，一个在东海岸，
but you know presumably a lot of clients on the east coast and the west coast,
但是东海岸和西海岸的很多客户端，
will gonna hit the same,
将会命中相同的，
or the two,
或者两个，
the memcached server on the west coast
西海岸的 memcached 服务器，
and memcached server east coast,
和东海岸的 memcached 服务器，
hold that key,
持有那个键，
and so that's not gonna be that good, right,
那就不太好了，
because like you know that single server might actually get overloaded
因为单个服务器可能会超载，
and it turns out the key distribution varies widely,
事实证明，键分发的差异很大，
and so that's not so good.
所以这并不是很好。
And so to solve problems like that,
所以，要解决这样的问题，
and the second sort of approach is to replicate, replicate data,
第二种方法是复制，复制数据，
so here is partition data and then is replicate data,
这里是分区数据，然后是复制数据，
that's great you know for hot keys,
这对热的键来说很好，
if you can take the same key propagated on a bunch of different memcached servers,
如果你可以使相同的键扩展到不同的 memcached 服务器，
then the clients that all hit that key
然后，所有命中这个键的客户端
can be spread across you know those memcached servers
都可以分布在这些 memcached 服务器上，
and get the keys basically in parallel,
并且并行地获得键，
and so that it works actually good for hot keys.
所以，这对热键很有效。
It doesn't really increase you know capacity,
它并不能增加容量，
so you just just takes more,
所以你需要更多的，
and in some ways we can see this in the previous picture,
在某些方面，我们可以在上一张图片中看到，
we have replication in action here,
我们在这里进行了复制，
we have replicated one data center,
我们复制了一个数据中心，
you know from the west coast completely to the east coast,
从西海岸到东海岸，
that hasn't increase the total capacity for the memcached,
这并没有增加 memcached 的总容量，
because both memcache the memcache layers store store the same amount of data,
由于两个 memcache 层都存储了相同数量的数据，
and didn't increase the capacity of the memcache layer,
没有增加 memcache 层的容量，
but you know you're allowed to you know read from these two different and memcache layers
但是你允许读取两个不同的 memcache 层，
on the east and west coast in parallel.
并行的从东海岸和西海岸（读取）。
Okay?
好的?
So we see a little form of replication going on
所以我们看到了一种复制的小型形式，
and you might wonder like what else is left to be done?
你可能会想，还有什么事情要做吗？
And this comes to a question was asked a little bit earlier,
这就涉及到了之前提出的一个问题，
let's say you need more capacity, right,
比如，你需要更多的容量，
so well, one solution to you know more capacity,
所以，一个更多容量的解决方案，
even in a single data center,
即使在单个数据中心，
so forget that there's two data centers,
所以忘了有两个数据中心，
just look for things from the perspective of a single data center,
只从单个数据中心的角度来看，
we want more capacity,
我们想要更大的容量，
one option correct would be to
一个选择是，
whatever you buy more memcached servers,
你购买更多的 memcached 服务器，
and just keep buying more of them,
并继续购买更多的服务器，
and that turns out to be slightly problematic,
这里有一个小问题，
and one reason that that is problematic is,
这里有问题的一个原因是，
because these frontends talk to basically every memcache server,
因为这些前端与每个 memcache 服务器交互，
and so they,
所以它们，
you know almost at least for writes,
至少在写入方面，
you know we know that TCP connections open,
我们知道 TCP 连接打开，
and so there's a large number of TCP connections,
所以这里有大量的 TCP 连接，
and furthermore, as we, as I said before
此外，正如我之前所说的，
is actually a particular key hard, hit hard,
如果一个键命中很多，
then the, that doesn't really solved by shard,
这没有被分片解决，
so you can buy more machines,
你可以买更多的机器，
but there's that one keys hot and lives in one machine,
但是一个热键在一台机器里，
that actually is not going to improve your performance.
这不会提高你的性能。
So their next step in terms of performance improvement
所以，他们在性能改进方面的下一步，
is to actually replicate with inside a single data center.
是在单个数据中心内进行复制。
So, more performance, so this is this idea of clusters,
更高的性能，这就是集群的概念，
and this is really a story about replication.
这是一个关于复制的故事。
And so what they actually do is like,
所以他们做的是，
if we look at a single data center,
如果我们查看单个数据中心，
we got our storage layer,
我们有自己的存储层，
and then within the storage layer,
然后在存储层内，
basically we're gonna replicate a set of frontends,
我们要复制一组前端，
so here's frontend layer,
这是前端层，
and here's our memcache layer,
这是我们的 memcache 层，
I'm gonna take that and just replicate multiple times,
我要把它复制多次，
and they call this a cluster.
他们称为集群。
And the reason this is good you know is,
这个好的原因是，
this actually deals deal well with, its good for popular keys,
很好地解决了，对热门键有好处，
popular key, it will now be replicated you know potentially multiple clusters,
热门的键，它可能被复制到多个集群，
and so that is nice,
所以这很好，
second, it reduces the number of connections,
第二，它减少了连接的数量，
and this is actually particularly there are multiple reasons why this important,
有多个原因为什么这很重要，
it avoids what they call the,
它避免了，他们所说的，
avoids incast problems incast congestion,
避免 incast 拥塞问题，
as I said before,
就像我之前说的，
one of these frontends may have to retrieve 500,
其中一个前端必须获取 500 ，
you know whatever hundred you know tens to hundreds of keys,
几十到上百的键，
and so it will send them in parallel
它会并行地发送它们，
to all the particular memcache there important,
到所有重要的 memcache ，
they all respond,
它们都会做出响应，
and of course you know we have many, many more memcaches,
当然，我们有很多的 memcache ，
we're going to have much more parallelism,
我们将会有更多的并行性，
a lot of packets will come back exactly at the same time,
很多包同时返回，
they can easily into queue,
它们可以很容易地进入队列，
queues being overloaded or queues being full,
队列超载或队列已满，
and therefore packets getting dropped,
因此包被丢弃，
and so by reducing the number of connections,
所以，通过减少连接数量，
not actually every frontend talks to,
不是每个前端都访问，
you know reduces where responses are going to come back,
减少回来的响应，
and we avoid this incast congestion problem,
我们避免了这个 incast 拥堵问题，
and in general, sort of reduce the pressure of the network,
总的来说，这减轻了网络压力，
it's actually hard to build networks that have bi section bandwidth,
很难建立具有双向带宽的网络，
that could sustain a huge load,
可以承受巨大的负载，
and here by sort of making using replication,
这里通过使用复制，
basically network for one cluster really has to support that one cluster well.
一个集群的网络很好地支持了这个集群。
Now, now this is all good,
现在，这一切都很好，
of course you know this is the downside of a design,
当然，这个设计的缺点，
like this is that,
也就是，
if you have unpopular keys,
如果你有不受欢迎的键，
there's unpopular keys is gonna get stored in multiple regions,
不受欢迎的键将被存储在多个区域，
and basically you know do nothing,
基本上什么都不做，
or [] contribute to improvement in performance,
或者[]对性能的提高做出贡献，
and so in fact what they do is,
所以，他们所做的是，
they have one additional sort of pool that they have,
他们还有一个额外的池，
and they call this the regional pool,
他们称为区域池，
and applications can decide
应用程序可以决定
to store you know not so popular keys into the regional pool,
保存不是很受欢迎的键到区域池，
to stick it inside,
把它放在里面，
and so the these,
所以这些，
so they, they don't are replicated in times across all clusters,
所以它们不会在时间上跨所有集群复制，
so you can think about the regional pool being shared among multiple clusters,
你可以考虑区域池在多个集群之间共享，
and used for the less popular keys or less frequently used keys.
用于不太受欢迎的键或不太频繁使用的键。
Okay?
好的?
So is this going to help with popular keys,
那么，这会对流行的键有帮助吗，
because each cluster is gonna have its own memcache.
因为每个集群都会有自己的 memcache 。
Yeah, every cluster has its own memcache,
是的，每个集群都有自己的 memcache ，
has his own frontends,
有自己的前端，
has his own memcache,
有自己的 memcache ，
and basically users you know
基本上用户，
the users are basically load balance across all these clusters.
用户是负载均衡到所有这些集群的。
But this still does not increase capacity, right?
但这仍然不能增加容量，对吗？
This not increase capacity,
这没有增加容量，
if you want to increase capacity,
如果您想要增加容量，
the you,
你，
well, it increase capacity a little bit, correct,
好的，它稍微增加了一些容量，
because all the unpopular stuff is not being extra cache,
因为所有不受欢迎的内容都不在额外的缓存，
and stuck in the regional pool,
并被困在区域池中，
and so that space is now free to actually store other keys.
所以，这些空间现在可以存储其他键。
So to avoid incast congestion,
所以为了避免 incast 拥塞，
they would also reduce the number of shards per cluster, right?
它们还会减少每个集群的分片数量，对吗？
Yeah, don't increase, they don't grow it,
是的，不增加，他们不会增加它，
the alternative plan correct was not introduce clusters,
替代方案不是引入集群，
but basically keep growing the memcache's shards,
但会继续增加 memcache 分片，
with the number of shards in a single memcache,
在单个 memcache 中的分片数量，
and you know that has its own limitations.
它有自己的限制。
Makes sense, thank you.
理解了，谢谢。
Okay, well, so this sort of the base design,
好的，这是基本的设计，
except there are all kinds of performance challenges, that they had to resolve,
除了他们必须解决的各种各样的性能挑战，
most of these performance challenges really had to do with,
大多数这些性能挑战必须解决，
I think the way to think about is protecting the database.
我认为考虑的方式是保护数据库。
So, like go back to this picture, correct,
所以，回到这张图片，
we have now design apparently to support billions requests per second,
我们现在的设计显然能支持每秒数十亿次请求，
and but the storage layer itself you know is sharded,
但是存储层本身是分片的，
because certainly not you know sustain billions requests per second,
因为肯定不能承受每秒支持数十亿次请求，
and it would be a disaster,
这会是一个灾难，
if for example, let's say all the memcaches failed in some way or another
假设所有的 memcache 都以这样或那样的方式失败了，
or whole cluster failed,
或整个集群出现故障，
and all the frontends you know would hit the storage servers,
所有前端都会命中存储服务器，
then you know the storage servers would fail over,
那么存储服务器会崩溃，
you know couldn't handle that kind of load,
不能处理这种负载，
and so they got to be very very careful with actually putting, doing anything,
所以他们必须非常非常小心做任何事情，
that requires more load on the storage servers.
需要在存储服务器上加载更多负载（的事情）。
So, so one for example challenge,
所以，比如一个挑战，
I'm going to talk about the number of them
我要谈的是，
is to bring up a new cluster,
建立一个新的集群，
you know easy way to bring up a new cluster
建立一个新集群的简单方法，
would be just to you know build a cluster,
就是建立一个集群，
turn the machines on, installed the software and then be done,
打开机器，安装软件，然后就完成了，
and basically rely on the fact,
基于这样一个事实，
that you know if the data is not in the cache,
如果数据不在缓存中，
you'll have miss
你会不命中，
and the miss will go to the database,
未命中会进入数据库，
actually you know collect the necessary data,
收集必要的数据，
and you know what's the problem about the kind of design?
这种设计有什么问题吗？
It's gonna have a lot of cache misses,
它会有很多缓存未命中，
because there's nothing in the cache.
因为缓存里什么都没有。
Yeah, for example, let's say you have you had one cluster,
是的，假设你有一个集群，
and you had the second cluster, right,
你有第二个集群，
you move half of your users to the second cluster, right,
你把一半的用户移动到第二个集群，
then 50% of your requests are going to miss in the cache,
那么 50% 的请求将在缓存中丢失，
and they're gonna hit the database,
它们会命中数据库，
and the database will fall over, correct.
数据库就会崩溃。
So how do they deal with this?
那么，他们是如何处理这一问题的呢？
Gutter?
Gutter ？
No, not the Gutter, this is the.
不，不是 Gutter ，这是。
I think they were making the new cluster
我认为他们让新集群
read some entries from the cache of an old cluster.
从旧集群的缓存中读取一些条目。
Yeah, gets in the new cluster,
是的，从新的集群获取，
if they miss in the new cluster,
如果它们在新集群中未命中，
they go to the old cluster from an existing one,
它们会转向旧的集群，从已经存在的那个，
and then they set in the new cluster,
然后它们在新集群中设置，
so basically one way to think about is,
所以考虑的一种方式是，
they fill up a new cluster or warm up a new cluster,
它们填充新的集群或预热新的集群，
by reading from an existing cluster,
通过从现有集群中读取，
and so that maybe increase the load on an existing cluster a little bit,
所以，这可能会稍微增加现有集群上的负载，
but at least don't actually put a lot of pressure on the database,
但至少不会给数据库带来太大压力，
as we see is the second,
我们稍后会看到，
that also introduces again some consistency issues,
这再次带来了一些一致性问题，
and you know we'll see that a little bit later.
我们稍后会看到这个。
Okay?
好的？
So that's one you know example of performance challenge the the address,
所以这是一个解决性能挑战的例子，
the other performance is popular term,
另一个性能是在受欢迎的术语，
used in many contexts, that are called the thundering herd problem,
在很多上下文中，称为惊群问题，
what's the thundering herd problem?
什么是惊群问题？
I guess when there are a lot of writes and reads
我想，当有大量的读写操作
approximately at the same time,
大致同时发生，
and because there are a lot of writes,
因为有大量的写操作，
the data will be invalidated many times,
数据将多次失效，
and the database will be assaulted with request.
数据库将受到请求的攻击。
Yeah, you can make it simpler,
是的，你可以让它变得简单，
like a single write cause an invalidation of a key, right,
单次写入导致一个键无效，
and anybody, any client that reads key right after it,
任何在它之后读取键的客户端，
so you could have the following situation,
所以，可能会出现以下情况，
you have a very very popular key,
你有一个非常受欢迎的键，
the you invalidate the key,
你使键失效，
so you delete the key from the cache,
所以你从缓存中删除键，
all the machines are on the frontends that meet popular key
所有在前端遇到流行键的机器
will do a get on that key,
会执行一次获取那个键，
all get back nil,
所有都得到 nil ，
and then they're all want to like read SELECT from the database, correct,
然后它们都想从数据库中读取 SELECT ，
and that you know might cost you know they put a lot of pressure on the database,
这可能给数据库带来很大的压力，
so, they want to avoid that problem,
所以，他们想要避免这个问题，
so how do they do that,
那么他们如何做的，
how do they avoid that problem?
他们如何避免这个问题？
They used leases.
他们用了租约。
Yeah, exactly, go ahead, say more.
是的，没错，继续，多说一点。
Yeah, I think they give like a time,
是的，我想他们给了一段时间，
like for key specific for for the user,
为用户指定的键，
and then like some like sometime,
然后在某个时刻，
what I understood, it was like kind of a lock,
据我所知，就像一把锁，
and then like if another user tries to to use it,
如果另一个用户试图使用它，
they would like wait
它们会等待，
and then hopefully it will be updated fast enough,
然后希望它能足够快地更新，
so that in the next retry, they'll get it.
在下一次重试时，他们就会得到它。
If you do a get, you get nil back,
如果你执行获取，你会获得 nil ，
you get two situations,
你有两种情况，
either you've got a lease, right,
要么你获取一个租约，
the first line basically that doesn't get and misses,
第一行没有得到和未命中，
you know gets release from memcached,
从 memcached 中获取释放，
and that memcached at least gives you the right to update
而 memcached 至少给你更新的权限，
or tells the clients,
或者告诉客户端，
like you know you're responsible for doing the update,
比如你要负责更新，
and if you don't,
如果你不这么做，
you know the first one,
你知道第一个，
then you get a basically a retry message or result,
你会收到一条重试消息或结果，
and that basically tells the client like oh you should retry it soon,
这告诉客户端，你应该尽快重试，
not immediately and maybe spread around a little bit,
不会立即出现，可能会扩散一点，
they probably do some binary backup type style thing,
他们可能会做一些二进制备份类型的事情，
and we try to get,
我们试着获取，
and in most cases the clients,
在大多数情况下，客户端，
that you know the first line that missed
未命中的第一行
will have updated the key k you know reasonably soon,
很快地更新键 k ，
like in the order of milliseconds,
在毫秒量级上，
and then these retries actual will succeed, right,
然后这些重试成功，
and and there's no really and there's no explosion
这里没有爆炸式增长，
on the number of requests to the database
对数据库的请求数量，
with this scheme.
在这种方案下。
Of course, it introduces,
当然，它引入了，
as we'll see in a second more you know race conditions,
正如我们稍后将看到的，更多的竞态条件，
but you know first let's keep focusing on performance.
但是，首先让我们继续关注性能。
There was another thing about leases, right,
租约还有另一件事，
where where they fit, like address still sets.
它们适合，比如地址仍然固定。
Yeah, so that leases form two roles,
是的，所以租约形成了两个角色，
as we'll see in a second,
我们稍后将看到，
one for consistency and one for performance,
一个是一致性，一个是性能，
this one is for performance,
这个是用来性能的，
and so we'll talk about consistency in a second,
我们将在稍后讨论一致性，
and I will see the second reviews,
我会看到第二次讨论，
as one way to solve one of these race conditions.
作为解决这些竞争情况的一种方法。
Okay, one more, there are many more in the paper,
好的，论文上还有更多，
but just one more that's sort of interesting,
还有一件有趣的事，
at least I find interesting,
至少我觉得有趣，
you know what happens if they have a memcached or memcache server failure?
如果 memcached 或 memcache 服务器出现故障，会发生什么情况？
It depends,
那得看情况,
if it's the whole data center that,
如果是整个数据中心，
the whole collection of memcache servers that failed.
整个 memcache 服务器集合都发生了故障。
Just consider a handful, I want to do.
只要考虑一个，我想要做的。
These kind that someone mentioned before,
之前有人提到过，
that the memcache the failed memcache,
故障的 memcache ，
but they don't delete them.
但他们不会删除它们。
Yeah, so look at the scenario, correct,
是的，所以看看这个场景，
problematic scenario is like a memcached server fails,
有问题的情况是 memcached 服务器出现故障，
that will result in a bunch of misses,
这将导致一系列未命中，
those misses will hit the database,
这些未命中将进入数据库，
and they want to avoid hitting the database, right,
他们想避免命中数据库，
any client that actually has a couple keys in those servers
任何在这些服务器中具有键的客户端，
and is gonna try to retrieve the key will fail,
试图获取键将会失败，
and then you know have to do something.
然后必须做点什么。
So when it get fails,
所以当它失败的时候，
you know the easy solution is to go to the database,
简单的解决办法就是去数据库，
but we want to protect the database,
但我们想要保护数据库，
and so that doesn't seem to be a great idea,
所以这看起来不是个好主意，
and so what they do is
所以，他们所做的是，
actually have a small other cluster or another pool,
拥有一个小型的其他集群或另一个池，
like the regional pool or they called the Gutter pool,
比如区域池或者他们叫 Gutter 池，
and the Gutter pool is basically sort of handful memcached machines,
Gutter 池就是一些 memcached 机器，
that is just available,
这只是可用的，
and they're available for a short period of time,
它们的使用时间很短，
the system sort of reconfigures and repairs itself,
系统在重新配置和修复自身，
and adds new memcached servers,
添加新的 memcached 服务器，
you know to to replace the one that failed.
替换失败的那个。
But in that period of time,
但在那段时间里，
you know there's a new order of minutes or maybe a little bit more,
有一个新的[顺序]，或者可能更多一点，
they don't want to get requests
它们不想收到请求，
or SELECT to go to the database,
或 SELECT 转到数据库，
instead of what they do when they get fails,
不是它们在失败时所做的事情，
you go try first the Gutter pool,
你先去试试 Gutter 池，
and you know the Gutter pool will,
Gutter 池将会，
you know the first one that hits the Gutter pool you know will fail or will miss,
第一个命中 Gutter 池的会失败或未命中，
do SELECT the database,
执行 SELECT 数据库，
get results stick into the Gutter pool,
将结果放入 Gutter 池，
and then subsequent request or gets will actually then be answered from the Gutter pool,
然后，后面的请求或获取将从 Gutter 池中得到答复，
and at some point, you know the memcached machine [] scaled,
在某个时刻， memcached 机器扩展，
it has either been replaced or replaced with another machine or recovered,
它或者被另一台机器替换或者恢复，
and then you know the loads shift back to this memcached server and the Gutter pool,
然后，负载将转移回 memcached 服务器和 Gutter 池，
so it's again in the side
它又一次在边上，
to sort of carry over between these sort of transition periods.
在这些过渡期之间进行。
Okay?
好的？
So this sort of gets us to the reading question for today,
这就是我们今天的阅读问题，
as you just mentioned,
就像你刚才提到的，
the Gutter pools you don't do a delete from the Gutter pool,
你不在 Gutter 池执行删除，
and invalidation is actually also not sent to the Gutter pool,
并且失效也不会被发送到 Gutter 池，
and the question is like why or can we speculate on why,
问题是为什么，或者我们可以推测为什么，
so maybe this is a good time for a quick breakout room,
所以也许这是一个快速分组会议室的时间，
couple minutes,
用几分钟时间，
you know to either discuss other aspects from the memcached design,
要么讨论一下 memcached 设计的其他方面，
or you want to discuss [] trying to figure out the answer to that question is.
或者你想要讨论这个问题的答案是什么。
So maybe we're gonna break up,
所以或许我们中断一下，
yes, thank you, Lily.
是的，谢谢， Lily 。
Okay, so is everybody back?
好的，大家都回来了吗？
Yep, it looks like it.
是的，看起来是的。
Yep, okay good.
是的，好的。
Okay, so anybody,
好的，有人知道，
you know the paper doesn't answer this question very precisely,
这篇论文没有非常准确地回答这个问题，
but anybody want to dare to speculate
但是有人想大胆猜测
what the answer is on the deletes,
删除的答案是什么，
no delete, you know no invalidation to the Gutter cluster.
没有删除，没有失效到 Gutter 集群。
Oh, what are.
哦，那个。
Go ahead.
继续。
Oh, what we said was something like,
哦，我们说的是，
if you do,
如果你这样做了，
then you would have a lot of pressure on the Gutter pool,
那么你会对 Gutter 池施加很大的压力，
because there are so few machines,
因为只有很少的机器，
and for every cache miss,
对于每个缓存未命中，
there are two requests for cache [] are just one,
有两个对缓存的请求，
so if you do that,
所以，如果你这样做，
after every write, you have an extra request,
在每次写入之后，你都会有一个额外的请求，
on the Gutter pool, it's so small,
在 Gutter 池上，它太小了，
so you don't want to do that,
所以你不会想这么做的，
and also you would protect the database as well,
此外，你还应该保护数据库，
because you would constantly query it after a write request.
因为你会在写入请求后不断地查询它。
Yeah, in general the delete messages also have to go to two pools, correct,
是的，删除消息需要去两个池，
the original memcached pool,
原始的 memcached 池，
all the memcached pools and invalidate it into the Gutter,
所有 memcached 池，并将其在 Gutter 失效，
and so you also double the delete traffic,
所以，删除流量也翻了一番，
so I think that's a perfectly,
所以我认为这是一个完美的，
I think that's the reason,
我想这就是原因，
it's a small set of machines,
这是一组很小的机器，
just there to sort of over
只是在那里
basically get through that transformation from a deleted memcached server,
完成从已删除的 memcached 服务器的转换，
failed memcached server to a new memcached server.
从出现故障的 memcached 服务器到新的 memcached 服务器。
Good.
好的。
Okay, so it's all I want to say about performance,
好了，关于性能，我想说的就是这些，
even though there's more in the paper about performance,
尽管论文中有更多关于性能的内容，
instead I want to talk a little bit about sort of these races,
相反，我想谈谈这些竞争，
and sort of come about,
它们来自，
because of this trying to achieve high performance,
因为这个试图获得高性能，
that I've been talking about.
我们已经讨论过的。
They're gonna be three races I want to talk about,
我想谈论的有三个竞争，
and in fact I think all three you already identified,
我认为你已经确认的三个，
and so [] most discussions presumably gonna be about,
大多数讨论都是关于，
how you know how do they avoid them.
他们是如何躲避它们的。
And so race 1 is what they call stale sets,
所以竞争 1 是他们所说的旧配置，
and scenario as follows,
场景如下，
we have client 1, use one region,
我们有客户端 1 ，使用一个区域，
nothing, one cluster nothing a particular special setup,
一个集群，没什么特别的设置，
so client 1 does get of k,
所以客户端 1 执行获取 k ，
you know that turns out to get a nil in the scenario,
在这种情况下，结果是 nil ，
it will read the value from the database,
它将从数据库中读取值，
maybe this is the client that actually got the token, correct,
也许这是获得 token 的客户端，
and it's the one that actually is allowed to set it,
它是被允许设置的那个，
but before it actually gets to set,
但在它设置之前，
another client you know comes in,
另一个客户端进来了，
and writes you know k is 2 to the database,
并将 k 为 2 写入数据库，
and then there's a put of k on 2
然后有一个 put(k,2) ，
and then you know the other clients,
然后其他客户端，
you know actually finally gets around to doing actual puts,
终于等到执行 put ，
you know that puts you know k comma and this is like maybe v1,
它执行 put(k, v1) ，
okay, comma v1,
好的， ,v1 ，
and now can we have a stale value in the cache,
现在，我们在缓存中有一个旧的值，
and that you know stale value is sort of permanent there,
而且在那里旧的值是持久性的，
until somebody else does an update,
在其他人更新之前，
okay,
好的,
and that sort of undesirable,
这是不希望的，
that really breaks their contract with the applications,
这破坏了与应用程序的契约，
and they don't want to go back in time,
它们不想回到过去，
you know would be [], actually user could observe that,
用户观察到它们，将是[]，
so want to try to avoid that.
所以试图避免这种情况。
So what they do, how do they solve this problem?
那么他们做了什么，他们如何解决这个问题？
Would use lease?
使用租约吗？
Yeah, great, some says it's the lease help out here,
是的，有人说是租约的帮助，
they already have a lease, correct,
它们已经有了租约，
because this guy got a lease for,
因为这个已经有了租约，
must have gotten lease,
已经获得租约，
because otherwise it's not reading from the database,
否则它就不会从数据库中读取数据，
and so at the client 1 presents this lease at the put,
所以，在客户端 1 在 put 上面加上租约，
or can put present to lease at the put,
或者可以在 put 上加上租约，
and in fact, it will
事实上，它会，
and what is the additional step basically?
还有额外的步骤是什么？
To check that the this hasn't expired or something,
检查这个没有过期或者什么，
because if the other client was able to.
因为如果另一个客户能够。
Sorry, I I mean I just realized I made a mistake,
抱歉，我刚意识到我犯了个错误，
so this is why the question is also not so good,
这就是为什么这个问题不是很好，
let me see the client 2 doesn't do put, correct,
让我看看，客户端 2 不会执行 put ，
that was invalidation consistency,
这是无效一致性，
I got myself confused here,
我在这里把自己搞糊涂了，
so what does the client actually the client 2 do,
那么客户端 2 做了什么，
after it sets the database.
在它设置数据库之后。
Go back.
回去。
Delete?
删除？
Yeah, it does delete,
是的，它执行删除，
for the reason that we talked about earlier, correct,
基于我们之前谈到的原因，
so it does delete of k,
所以它执行删除 k ，
and what's the side effect,
那么连带作用是什么，
of what happens with the lease of the k being deleted?
删除 k ，租约会发生什么？
But it doesn't like verify or it doesn't.
它不会验证，或者它不会。
Yeah, actually what happens is a side effect of the delete,
是的，删除的连带作用是，
the lease is invalidated,
租约失效，
so it invalidates the lease,
所以，它使租约失效，
and so when the put comes along,
所以当 put 出现时，
so my timeline is a little bit,
我的时间线有点，
you know this happens quite well before, right,
这个发生在之前，
so the put happens after the delete,
所以， put 在 delete 之后发生，
the put will present the lease that gotta get,
put 将带上 get 的租约，
but that lease has been invalidated by the delete,
但是租约已经因为删除而失效，
and so this put gets rejected.
所以这个 put 被拒绝了。
So basically one way to think about this is that,
所以考虑这个问题的一种方式是，
they leverage you know the lease mechanism to avoid the thundering herd problem,
他们利用租约机制来避免惊群问题，
they extended to basically also avoid this stale set problem.
也避免了这个旧设置的问题。
Right, does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
So, even if we don't have this lease invalidation mechanism,
所以，即使我们没有这个租约失效机制，
we would still obey the weak consistency,
我们仍然会服从弱一致性，
that you would have ordered writes that happened at some point in the past,
你会获得在过去的某个时间发生的顺序写入，
but I believe that,
但我相信，
the thing of this thing ensures that you observe your own writes, right?
这件事可以确保你观察到自己的写入，对吗？
You're sure, you're right,
你是对的，
they also ensures that you don't go back in time,
它们还能确保你不会回到过去，
like if you read something,
比如，如果你读到一些东西，
and like everybody else that comes you know after this client 2,
任何比客户端 2 更晚的客户端，
will see you know the old v1
将会看到旧的 v1 ，
and so a client might get well behind
客户端可能会远远落后于，
and not see that new write for long, long periods of time,
很长一段时间都看不到新的写入，
in fact, might seen not at all.
事实上，可能一直看不到。
Yeah, but, I mean would this be actually going back in time,
是的，但是，我是说，这会回到过去吗，
because clients did not read anything after.
因为客户端没有读取之后的东西。
Maybe maybe back in time is the wrong word,
或许回到过去是个错误的词，
but it won't observe v2 for a long, long time.
但它在很长一段时间内不会观察到 v2 。
I see, okay.
我明白了，好的。
That was not something that we wanted to happen,
这不是我们想要发生的事情，
it's okay to be a little bit,
有一点是可以的，
but not you know for a long, long time.
但在很长一段时间是不可以的。
Okay, second race which you know guys already mentioned,
好的，第二个竞争已经有人提过了，
already identified too,
已经被确认了，
because advantage of many I guess lab debugging,
因为很多实验调试的优势，
you know all about the races,
都是关于竞争的，
race 2 and this is the cold cluster race,
竞争 2 ，这是冷集群竞争，
and sort of in a similar style,
风格也差不多，
we have two clients,
我们有两个客户端，
client 1, client 2.
客户端 1 ，客户端 2 。
And, let's say k is v1 originally
假设 k 最初是 v1 ，
and so [] both clients are in the cold cluster,
两个客户端都在冷集群中，
client 1 sets the k to a new value in the database,
客户端 1 在数据库中将 k 设置为新值，
delete the k in the cold cluster, correct,
删除冷集群中的 k ，
current cluster actually in,
当前集群所在的，
and then this client does get in the cold cluster,
然后这个客户端在冷集群中执行获取，
sees that it actually is not there,
看到它不在那里，
and what is gonna do,
接下来要做的是，
get from the warm cluster, get the value back,
从暖集群中获取，获取值，
I mean that like you know get actually gets there,
我的意思是，从那里获取，
before actually the the cold cluster or the warm cluster actually has been updated.
在冷集群或暖集群更新之前。
And so now it will do a set of you know this key to v1
现在，它将执行设置 k v1 ，
or put sorry, let me be consistent,
或者 put ，抱歉，让我修改一下，
put k to v1 in the cold cluster
在冷集群中将 k 设置为 v1 ，
and now we have to sort of the same situation as before,
现在我们有和以前一样的情况，
and where you know we have sort of a permanent stale value in the cold cluster.
我们在冷集群中有一个永久的旧的值。
And how do they solve that problem?
他们如何解决这个问题？
Anybody remember?
有人记得吗？
So they have a small extension that avoids this problem,
他们有一个小的扩展来避免这个问题，
and guess what it could be, if you.
猜猜是什么。
Whether C1 is the warm cluster or cold cluster?
C1 是暖集群还是冷集群？
Both the cold clusters.
两个都是冷集群。
And they're different, they're in different cold clusters, right?
它们在不同的冷集群中，对吗？
I'm not sure that matters.
我不确定这有什么关系。
Yeah, actually, it doesn't.
是的，没什么关系。
Anybody?
有人知道吗？
I think they mentioned like hold-off for two seconds,
我想他们提到过要推迟两秒钟，
though [entirely] shared all the details of that.
尽管完全分享了所有的细节。
Yeah, the basically the, this actually causes they put hold-off,
是的，这导致了推迟，
they call this a hold-off, of two-second hold-off,
他们称之为推迟两秒，
on any set to that key,
任何对这个键的设置，
so this particular after you do a delete in the cold cluster,
在你从冷群集中删除之后，
you can't do any sets to that key for two seconds,
你在两秒钟内不能对那个键做任何设置，
and so this particular put will be rejected,
所以，这个 put 会被拒绝，
and this is only during the warm up to their phase, right,
这只是在预热阶段，
so when the cluster comes up, it's cold,
当集群出现时，它是冷的，
you know for a couple hours it runs,
在几个小时的运行之后，
you know to start warming up,
开始预热，
and get its content in place,
并将其内容就位，
and once you know sort of warmed up,
一旦热身完成，
then you know they stopped doing this trick,
他们就不再使用这个技巧了，
but basically sort of you know just [] this problem over,
但是,针对这个问题，
they think two seconds is sufficient,
他们认为两秒钟足够了，
and that sufficient for basically that write to propagate to the cold database too.
这也足以让写入传播到冷数据库。
Okay?
好的？
But there's one more write the problem is,
但还有一个写入问题是，
let me quickly mention that,
让我快速说一下，
because again you already mentioned it,
因为你们已经提到了，
so race number 3 that they talked about in the paper,
所以他们在论文中讨论的竞争 3 ，
and I'm sure there's more,
我相信还有更多，
but you know the one they say,
但是他们说的那个，
that the one they talk to the paper about,
在论文中说的那个，
and this is between regions,
这是在不同区域之间，
it has to do with the primary backup problem,
它必须处理主备问题，
primary backup.
主备。
It's sort of a similar problem,
这是一个类似的问题，
and where you know the client 1 does write to the database,
客户端 1 写入到数据库，
the database,
数据库，
and this is a client in the backup,
这是在 backup 的一个客户端，
so this is a backup clients in the backup region,
这是在备区的客户端，
so that's write to the database in the primary region,
它写入主区域的数据库，
that sort of goes off and then this delete of the key,
继续，然后删除这个键，
in of course the backup region,
当然在备区域中，
from it's cache,
从它的缓存中，
and then in principle it would do immediately,
然后它会立即起作用，
and this is like one of you mentioned this,
你们中的一个提到了，
like you can either do get that particular k, right,
你可以获取那个 k ，
then, and and won't see the, will fetch on the,
然后，不会看到，将从取回，
yeah, you know it won't see actually the result of that write,
是的，它不会看到那个写入的结果，
so we won't see its own write,
所以我们不会看到它自己的写入，
because of write is still on the way to the backup or to the primary,
因为写入还在到主或备的路上，
the primary will send through the sql thing, squeal thing,
primary 通过 squeal 发送，
propagate update to the database in the backup area,
将更新传播到备区域中的数据库，
and so only then you know again the backup will actually in the backup area,
只有到那时，备区域，
in the backup region will actually see the k change,
在备区域中将看到 k 的变化，
so we're sort of, we have a problem here, right,
所以我们这里有个问题，
where if this k would proceed without any modifications,
如果这个 k 在没有任何修改的情况下继续，
then, we would see not our own writes.
那么，我们就看不到自己的写入了。
And anybody remember how they solve this problem?
有人记得，他们是怎么解决这个问题的吗？
Was this remote marker?
是远程标记吗？
Yeah, absolutely, it is,
是的，它是，
so when they delete k key k,
所以当他们删除键 k 时，
and they are they may, they, they keep it in the memcached of the backup,
他们可能把它保存在 backup 的 memcached 中，
and mark it as remote,
并将其标记为远程，
and so when this the client 1 does get,
所以，当客户端 1 执行 get ，
they'll see, hey, I'm gonna get,
它们会知道，嘿，我要获取，
basically gets remote back from its local memcache,
从它的本地内存缓存远程取回，
and then goes basically to fetch it from the primary, from primary region.
然后从主区域获取它。
Okay?
好的？
But then the the remote marker will be removed,
但之后远程标记将被移除，
when it's safe to read from the backup.
当可以安全地从 backup 中读取时。
Yes, I think one of the database,
是的，我认为其中一个数据库，
the backup database gets the data from the primary,
备数据库从主数据库获取数据，
that can remove the marker,
它可以移除标记，
because then it's safe to read from the primary database, from the backup database.
因为这样就可以安全地从备数据库读取。
Does that make sense?
这能理解吗？
Okay, so let me do a quick summary,
好的，让我做个简短的总结，
and because I'm running a little bit over time,
因为我已经有点超时了，
so quick summaries, you know caching is vital,
快速总结一下，缓存是至关重要的，
basically get in capacity that we're talking about this paper,
我们所讨论的这篇论文的能力，
like billions of operations per second,
每秒数十亿次操作，
there are two strategies to sort of get this high capacity,
有两种策略可以获得这种很高的能力，
one is partitioning,
一个是分区，
which gives you parallelism or sharding,
给你带来了并行性或分片，
and the other strategy is you know replication,
另一种策略是复制，
is really good for hot keys,
对热键来说很好，
keys are being requested by lots and lots of clients,
被很多客户端请求的键，
so that's the keys get replicated on multiple machines.
键被复制到多个机器上。
And you know we also see you know there's a bunch of almost adhoc techniques
我们还看到，有很多特别的技术，
to sort of get around some of the serious consistency issues, that are pop up,
为了绕过一些出现的严重的一致性问题，
even if the systems are designed to give weak consistency,
即使系统被设计成提供弱一致性，
and so this whole sort of consistency
所以，整个一致性，
between the database, between db and caches or memcache is tricky,
在数据库和缓存 memcache 之间的是困难的，
maybe much more tricky than you might thought,
可能比你想象的要复杂得多，
because of memcache, the cache you know what could be the problem,
因为缓存可能成为问题，
but you know as you can see, it's actually pretty tricky,
正如你所看到的，这是相当困难的，
in fact there's a more quite a bit of research going on,
事实上，有更多的研究正在进行，
trying to figure out how could you do better.
试图解决怎样才能做得更好。
Okay, with that I want to conclude,
好了，这是我想总结的，
that people that need to run, can run,
那些需要走的人，可以走，
you know go to their next Zoom meeting,
去参加他们的下一个 Zoom 会议，
and I'll see you around,
我们会再见，
or answer any questions, if you have any questions remaining,
或者回答任何问题，如果你有任何问题，
and otherwise, I'll see you on Thursday, thank you.
否则，我们周四见，谢谢。
Sorry, I have a question about,
抱歉，我有个问题，
so, for example, for the last thing we talked about with the remote marker,
对于我们讨论的最后一件事，远程标记，
how did they know that this is gonna be a relevant data race,
他们怎么知道这是一个相关的数据竞争，
or how did they decide that,
或者他们是如何决定，
it is going to be more useful to do this additional stuffs of remote marker
做这些额外的远程标记会更有用，
versus just getting stale data.
而不是只获取旧数据。
Well, I think there is because they have this requirement right up front,
好的，我想这是因为他们事先有这个要求，
although the paper didn't really stipulate very clearly,
尽管论文并没有明确规定，
they really want this,
他们真的很想要这个，
like, for example you do, a user adds something to their timeline,
比如，用户在他们的时间线上添加一些东西，
read it again, and it's not there,
再读一遍，它不在那里了，
and so that is a thing that could be observed directly by users
所以，这是用户可以直接观察到的东西，
and strange inconsistency,
奇怪的，不一致，
and they they they want to avoid that.
他们想要避免这种情况。
Okay, that makes sense, that makes sense.
好的，理解了，理解了。
And my other question was,
我的另一个问题是，
on the one of the first slides where you had invalidation of the memcache.
在最初的一张 memcache 失效的幻灯片上。
Let me find where I had that.
让我找找，我把它放在哪里了。
Oh, here.
哦，这里。
Well, yeah, this is the slide like a little bit wild now, but.
是的，这是那个幻灯片，有一点乱。
Oh, no, it was one of the later ones.
哦，不是，是后面那一张。
Also have some invalidation on it or it doesn't.
有一些无效，或者它没有。
Maybe the next one.
也许是下一张。
Yes.
好的。
Yeah, yeah, so the client is going to set the invalidation only for its local region,
是的，所以客户端仅为本区域设置无效，
and the squeal is going to do it,
squeal 会取执行，
what the transfer and for the non-local.
转移到非本地。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, make sense, thank you so much.
好的，理解了，非常感谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。
Professor, I had two.
教授，我有两个。
You had your final question,
你问了你的最后一个问题，
sorry sorry sorry, go ahead, please ask your questions.
抱歉，抱歉，请继续提问。
These after class.
这些都是课后的。
They don't count.
它们不算数。
So for servers servers in in a region are assigned,
所以，对于区域中分配的服务器，
when we have clusters, each one are assigned to a cluster, right?
当我们有集群时，每个都分配到集群中，是吗？
Yeah yeah yeah, every clusters really replicate.
是的，每个集群都复制了。
Okay, nice, yeah.
好的，很好，是的。
I mean like like servers are assigned to one single replica.
我的意思是，服务器被分配给一个复制。
Nice, and then the second one was like straight from the paper and very precise,
好的，然后第二个是论文中很明确，
but it says, like okay here,
但它说的，好的，这里，
in I think generic cache page two,
我想，在第二页的通用缓存页中，
it says like use memcache as more general key-value store,
它说使用 memcache 作为更通用的键值存储，
and particularly say,
特别说到，
it takes little effort for new services to leverage the existing marcher infrastructure
新服务利用现有的基础设施只需付出很小的努力，
without the burden of tuning optimizing provisioning and maintaining a large server fleet,
而没有调整、优化、配置、维护大型服务器集群的负担，
so I wasn't sure and I looked up,
我不确定，我看了看，
and I couldn't find what like what's existing marcher infrastructure.
我找不到现有的基础设施是什么。
I don't actually know exactly what they're referring to, so.
我其实不知道他们指的是什么，所以。
Okay, all right, cool, thanks.
好的，好的，谢谢。
[].
[]。
See you.
再见。
I wanted to pull up on a question,
我想问一个问题，
that I think well you master about a certain failure mode,
我想你说了某种失败模式，
if memcached server fails,
如果 memcached 服务器出现故障，
I think there's,
我觉得，
I'm trying to think which slide would be helpful to look at,
我在想哪张幻灯片会对我有所帮助，
was earlier,
早一点，
maybe that one you just,
也许是刚才那个，
just anything that kind of shows memcached,
任何显示 memcached 的，
the the overall system diagram I guess.
我想是整个系统图。
Okay, well, the multiple [],
好的，有多个[]，
but this is the one basically if you think about as a single cluster, if you will.
但如果你愿意的话，你可以认为这是一个集群。
Yeah, okay.
好的，好的。
Yeah.
好的。
Look at another one,
查找另一个，
but I think this is sort of probably good enough.
但我认为这可能已经足够了。
Yeah, I think this is, this is good,
是的，我觉得这很好，
yeah, I think this question was,
是的，我想这个问题是，
so, try to,
所以，试着，
but it was something about like,
但这就像是，
if a client frontend writes,
如果客户端前端写入，
yeah, if a client writes to its memcached server,
是的，如果客户端向它的 memcached 服务器写入，
and that memcached server crashes,
然后那个 memcached 服务器崩溃，
and then the client immediately tries,
然后客户端立即尝试，
then which is presumably switches to another memcached server,
然后可能会切换到另一台 memcached 服务器，
and then read it again,
然后再次读取，
what mechanism makes sure it doesn't see that it's a result of its previous write.
什么机制确保它不会看到它之前写入的结果。
I I think what happens is we probably go to the Gutter,
我认为发生的事情是，我们很可能会去 Gutter ，
when the memcached fails, correct,
当 memcached 失败时，
client will get no response back,
客户端将不会收到响应，
and when that no response comes back,
当没有回应的时候，
it actually goes to the Gutter,
它会去 Gutter ，
which has nothing in it,
里面什么都没有，
probably in the first try,
可能在第一次尝试时，
and will read it from whatever database.
将从数据库中读取它。
Oh, okay, okay, that that makes sense.
哦，好的，理解了。
And yeah, it's a little bit unclear,
是的，这有一点不清楚，
exactly what happens when a new machine gets added,
当添加一台新机器时到底会发生什么，
you know they don't really talk much about in the paper,
他们并没有在论文中谈论太多，
I presume this is actually consistent [action] part,
我认为这是一致性部分，
where keys will be automatically shifted from one machine to another.
其中键自动从一台机器转移到另一台机器。
I guess, what if there were multiple clusters,
我想，如果有多个集群，
wouldn't it not,
难道不是，
maybe I just need to read about the Gutter,
或许我只需要从 Gutter 中读取，
but wouldn't it potentially shift to another memcached,
但它会不会潜在地转移到另一个 memcached ，
and oh actually, yeah.
哦，是的。
I think it always when get fails,
我想每次 get 失败时，
the client goes to the Gutter.
客户端去 Gutter 。
Right.
好的。
Okay, yeah, these clusters are kind of self-contained,
好的，是的，这些集群是自己管理的，
each have a the memcached.
每个都有 memcached 。
Okay, okay, that makes, yeah that makes sort of sense, thank you.
好的，好的，理解了，谢谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。
Follow follow up on that,
跟进这个问题，
when it falls back to the Gutter,
当它到 Gutter 时，
or what is like two different clusters,
如果两个不同的集群，
their memcache server fails at the same time,
它们的 memcache 服务器同时出现故障，
and so they both go to the Gutter,
所以它们都去了 Gutter ，
and now doing like concurrent writes to the Gutter,
现在对 Gutter 进行并发写入，
how do we ensure that those writes don't go out of order?
我们如何确保这些写入不会打乱顺序？
You know they do sets, correct,
它们执行设置，
and the the writes always go to the database to the primary,
写操作总是到数据库到 primary ，
the primary orders all of them,
primary 对它们进行排序，
so I think writes are always ordered,
我想写入总是有顺序的，
the only thing that you know the clients might do is
客户端可能会做的唯一一件事是
you know set a value in or put a value into the kv server,
set 或 put 一个值到 kv 服务器，
but then they have done that after they read from the database.
但它们必须之后从数据库读取。
Right, so what if someone is like doing a, they do a read,
好的，如果有人执行一个读取，
and then they're setting it into the database,
然后他们将其设置到数据库中，
but like let's say two different clusters fail,
假设两个不同的集群失败，
and then I'm not sure if this possible actually,
我不确定这是否可能，
but let's say like one, cluster one first reads from the key, gets back the value,
但是假如集群 1 首先读取键，获取到值，
and then there's a write in between,
然后在中间有一个写入，
and then the second cluster then reads,
然后，第二个集群读取，
and then they both try to put into their memcache servers,
然后它们都试着放入它们的 memcache 服务器，
but, but let's say those servers failed.
但是，假设这些服务器出了故障。
Yeah, maybe, maybe,
是的，也许，也许，
yeah, it's a good question,
是的，这是个好问题，
I think there's all kinds of little corner cases,
我认为有各种各样的边界情况，
that actually not describe the case,
没有描述这个情况，
I I think maybe leases will help out,
我觉得租约也许能帮上忙，
because that server you're gonna set to does have the lease,
因为你要设置的服务器有租约，
for, the first one we did get a lease back correct to the set,
我们第一次拿回了设置的租约，
and if in the meantime,
在此期间，
the servers gets replaced,
服务器被替换，
the replacement server does not know that actually the lease was granted,
替换的服务器不知道租约已被授予，
and so will reject the set,
因此会拒绝设置，
I'm just speculating, correct.
我只是在猜测。
Okay, yeah, so for the Gutter,
好的，是的，所以对于 Gutter 来说，
how does it control leases there?
它是如何控制租约的？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Okay, I see.
好的，我明白了。
Sorry, I can speculate,
抱歉，我可以推测，
but you know you know certainly I don't know.
但是，其实我不知道。
What would you say, if you had to speculate?
如果让你去推测，你会怎么说？
Well, I would first have to go sit down
好的，我得先去坐下来，
and think a little bit about it.
好好想一想。
Okay, makes sense, yeah, thank you.
好的，有道理，是的，谢谢。
I have a bit of a tangential question,
我有一个离题的问题，
which is, I thought it was really cool,
我认为这很酷，
that they were using UDP for the get request and TCP for the others,
他们对 get 请求使用 UDP ，对其他请求使用 TCP ，
and I was wondering how common that is,
我想知道这有多普遍，
is that like a very standard thing to do?
这是一件非常标准的事情吗？
Yes, yes and no,
是的，是的，也不是，
it is, you know I think people prefer generally to use TCP
它是，我认为人们通常更喜欢使用 TCP
provides reliability ordering and all the good great stuff,
提供可靠性排序和所有好的东西，
but there's real overheads with it,
但它有开销，
you know like the you know the state that needs to be maintained for connections,
需要维护连接的状态，
for connection,
对于连接，
and so there's always a little bit of struggle,
所以总会有一些挣扎，
when machines a lot of incoming TCP connection,
当机器有大量传入的 TCP 连接时，
a lot of outbound connections,
有很多出站连接，
that always causes problems,
这总会带来问题，
and in the default, you know if you run into that problem is
在默认情况下，如果你遇到这个问题，
to basically do UDP type stuff.
基本上是做 UDP 类型的东西。
Sometimes.
有时候。
Like normal from this paper?
这篇论文中的是正常的吗？
No, not from this paper.
不，不是从这篇论文。
Some people like to roll their own sort of like reliably transport protocol over UDP.
有些人喜欢在 UDP 上使用他们自己的类似可靠传输协议的技术。
Like QUIC?
比如 QUIC ？
Yep, for example.
是的，是个例子。
Because they mentioned they also do like sequence numbers UDP connections done.
因为他们提到他们也做了 UDP 连接的序列号。
But persumably [] congestion windows and all the other scaling
但毫无疑问地[]拥塞窗口和所有其他扩展，
and all the other TCP features that TCP has.
以及 TCP 拥有的所有其他 TCP 功能。
Thank you.
谢谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。
So, another, oops, sorry, go ahead.
所以，另一个，糟糕，抱歉，请继续。
Okay, I guess, I just wanted to quickly ask about
好的，我想，我是想快速问一下
kind of the replication between the different clusters,
不同集群之间的复制，
but basically they don't do any formal replication.
但是，它们不会进行任何正式的复制。
Yeah, that correctly,
是的，没错，
well, yeah, no, well, yes or no, right,
好的，不，好的，是或不是，
because you know the database need to be updated,
因为数据库需要更新，
hold on, hold on,
等等，等等，
let me actually go back
让我回去一下，
and make sure you know what you're talking about.
确保知道你在说什么。
Let's see clusters,
让我们来看看集群，
yeah, we have multiple clusters,
是的，我们有多个集群，
yeah there's no real replication going on between the clusters, right,
是的，集群之间没有真正的复制，
because there's one single storage in there.
因为只有一个存储。
Right, and so there are kind of like depending on these leases
好的，所以有一些类似于根据这些租约
to keep the cache is up-to-date or.
来保持缓存最新或者。
The the every cluster is completely independent,
每个集群都是完全独立的，
they have nothing to do with each other,
它们之间没有任何关系，
and users are divided over these [],
用户根据这些[]拆分，
and so one user talks to one cluster,
所以，一个用户访问一个集群，
and and then you know within the cluster, you know they use leases or,
然后在集群内部，他们使用租约或，
and this database invalidates leases and keys.
这个数据库使租约和键无效。
Right, got it, okay,
好的，明白了，好的，
yeah, so it's like the squeal and the storage.
是的，所以就像 squeal 和存储。
Yeah, all the writes basically in just go through this storage, correct,
是的，所有的写入都会通过这个存储，
all writes go through here,
所有的写入都要经过这里，
they get ordered,
它们被排序了，
and you know they pop out invalidation messages.
它们会发出失效消息。
Got it [], thank you.
明白了，谢谢。
Yeah, go ahead.
好的，继续。
Yeah, so tangential question,
是的，所以这个离题的问题，
I guess I'm not sure this is,
我想我不确定，
because of the way we've kind of presented papers in the class,
因为我们在课堂上展示论文的方式，
but it kind of seems like,
但这看起来有点像，
the way these systems are developed is,
这些系统的开发方式是，
like okay, we have like these these systems,
比如，好的，我们有这样的系统，
like our needs are continuing to scale,
我们的需求在继续扩大，
so let's like maybe this is also not an accurate representation,
所以我们，也许这也不是一个准确的表达，
but it sounds like, let's add another layer to kind of handle this load,
但这听起来像是，让我们再增加一层来处理这个负载，
or that kind of you know cache something
或者缓存的东西，
or add another layer of complexity on top of it,
或者在它上面增加另一层复杂性，
is it fair to say that,
这样说是否公平，
like system development has generally been like,
系统开发通常是这样的，
let's just add another layer to kind of deal with.
让我们再加一层来处理。
Yes or no,
是或不是，
I think the designer took a very pragmatic approach,
我认为设计者采取了非常务实的方式，
you know figure out like run into a real problem and solve the real problem,
弄清楚遇到了真正的问题，解决真正的问题，
and in basically you think about it not a lot of additional mechanism
从根本上来说，并不是很多额外的机制，
to actually make it all work,
才能让这一切正常工作，
so in terms of,
所以从这个角度来说，
I mean I mean I think it's pretty impressive and this kind of performance,
我的意思是，这种性能是非常令人印象深刻的，
with off shelf components,
使用现成的组件，
the absolute people also go back once in a while,
当然，人们也会偶尔回去，
said okay, how would I design a system to get better performance
我该如何设计一个系统来获得更好的性能，
and don't for example have this inconsistency between the database and caches,
不会有数据库和缓存之间的这种不一致，
and you know it actually turns out to be a research problem,
这实际上是一个研究问题，
because people figured out how to do that,
因为人们知道如何做到这一点，
and so you'll see recent research papers that describe alternative solutions,
你会看到描述替代解决方案的最新研究论文，
or new components of the solution,
或解决方案的新组件，
because like you know any of the [] I know of,
因为我所知道的[]，
you know cannot support a billion operations per second.
不能支持每秒 10 亿次操作。
Yeah, right.
是的，好的。
Okay, that's interesting, thank you.
好的，这很有趣，谢谢。
Yeah, this is fascinating stuff,
是的，这是很吸引人的东西，
it's like a real world system design.
这是一个真实世界的系统设计。
I have one more question, if you don't mind.
如果你不介意的话，我还有一个问题。
Yeah, go ahead.
是的，继续。
So in the design here,
所以在这里的设计中，
where they replicate across different regions,
它们在不同的地区复制，
so sorry, just to clarify when the first clarification question I have is,
抱歉，我要确认第一个问题是，
when they were okay against different regions,
当它们在不同的区域表现良好时，
each region has a bunch of internal clusters, right.
每个区域都有一堆内部集群，对吧。
And then, my follow-up question to that is,
然后，我的后续问题是，
it seems like everything is,
看起来一切都是，
yeah everything is hitting the primary storage,
是的，所有东西都在访问主存储，
if let's say we wanted to scale up,
假设我们想要扩大规模，
so that we didn't have all the writes hitting the primary storage,
这样我们不会让所有写操作都命中主存储，
how would you go about designing.
你将如何着手设计。
Yeah, my suspicion is that,
是的，我的想法是，
they're actually a design describe,
它们是一种设计描述，
okay, so there's a bunch of points,
好的，这里有很多要点，
there's a whole other paper on this topic
关于这个主题还有一整篇论文
about actually how to do the replication,
是关于如何进行复制的，
so this is not the only Facebook paper on scaling things up
这并不是 Facebook 上唯一一篇关于扩大规模的论文，
and there's a system was published in 2015 or [],
有一个系统是在 2015 年或[]发布的，
were you know they have a scalable design to propagate these writes,
他们有一个可扩展的设计来传播这些写入，
my suspicion is also that
我的想法也是，
they will have a shard the users to a particular regions,
他们会根据用户分片到不同的区域，
and make some regions the primary for those users.
并使一些区域作为那些用户的 primary 。
I see, so they assigned different regions primaries for different shards.
我明白了，所以他们为不同的分片分配了不同的区域 primary 。
Yeah, I think so,
是的，我想是的，
that's why I would do, we're trying to do,
这是我会做的，尝试做的，
and I'm speculating here.
我在这里推测。
Would it be a wise decision to do like consensus protocol across the storage layers,
像跨存储层的共识协议是不是明智的决定，
or would that just be like too high you know.
或者会不会太高了。
You could do that, like Spanner does that, correct.
你可以这样做，比如 Spanner 这样做了。
Right.
是的。
And how fast is Spanner?
Spanner 有多快？
Pretty fast.
挺快的。
You look back into it back into the table,
你回取看看，看看表格，
how many transactions per second could do?
每秒可以处理多少事务？
I do not remember the exact number.
我记不清确切的数字了。
I think about a hundred.
我想大概有一百个。
Oh, oh.
哦，哦。
In fact, for I think write [] 10.
事实上，我想写入是 10 。
Right, this is for write transactions, right.
是的，这是写入事务。
Right, the write, the write transactions are very slow.
是的，写入事务很慢。
Sorry, I think I realized that
抱歉，我想我意识到，
I do not understand race 1.
我不理解竞争 1 。
Okay, let me see if I can replicate it,
好的，让我看看能不能复制它，
now, let's see where we race 1.
让我们看看竞争 1 在哪里。
I think I'm just confused what is v2.
我想我只是搞不懂什么是 v2 。
Um, v2 is this right,
v2 是右边这个，
hold on, I'll mark it.
稍等，我来做个记号。
Okay.
好的。
And the problem is that,
问题是，
it is like wedged in between the first one.
它是夹在第一个中间。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, so like, we wanted it to be deleted,
好的，我们想把它删除，
so that the next person can read,
以便下一个人可以读取，
refresh it from the database,
从数据库中刷新它，
but now it's there with the old value.
但现在它仍然保持着旧的值。
Yeah, so basically we have a permanent stable value,
是的，所以我们有一个永久稳定的值，
really the issue is this permanent [business],
真正的问题是这个永久的[业务]，
or you know permanent between quotes, correct,
或者带引号的 permanent ，
because it's a cache,
因为这是个缓存，
but like you know this, this put,
但是这个 put ，
that came after you know basically the k be k the k being updated to v2,
之后 k 被更新为 v2 ，
so we have k 2 here really, correct,
所以我们这里有 k 2 ，
that's what the right value should be,
这是正确的值，
and here actually this is v1,
这里实际上是 v1 ，
so let's say there's just 1,
所以我们假设只有 1 ，
what we've done here is,
我们在这里所做的是，
we put a k 1 in after,
我们 put(k,1) 之后，
and that's just not the right thing,
这不是一件正确的事情，
everybody that comes after now and does a get on k, correct,
每个这个之后的，执行 get k ，
is gonna get 1 back instead of 2.
会获得 1 而不是 2 。
Okay, that makes sense, okay.
好的，理解了，好的。
Including client 2, which is going to be bizarre.
包括客户端 2 ，这将是奇怪的。
Right, right, okay, that makes sense, thank you so much.
好的，好的，理解了，非常感谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。
I think the part in the beginning about the evolution
我想开始关于进化的部分，
was also pretty helpful, I think.
我认为也很有帮助。
Okay, good good.
好的，很好。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
You're welcome.
不用谢。